<resources>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Veg Doctor</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">Designed &amp; Developed by AGTRAIN Trading</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>
    <string name="menu_about">About</string>
    <string name="menu_about_agtrain">About AgTrain</string>
    <string name="menu_about_hort_life_project">About Horti-Life Project</string>
    <string name="menu_references">References</string>

    <string name="tab_text_1">Description</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">Products</string>
    <string name="tab_text_3">Images</string>


    <string name="pest">Pest</string>
    <string name="disease">Disease</string>
    <string name="disorder">Disorder</string>


    <string name="title_activity_detail_information">DetailInformationActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dis_order_list">DisOrderListActivity</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->

    <string name="app_name">Veg Doctor</string>
    <string name="app_Name_For_Splash">Ethiopian Vegetable Pests and Disease Guide</string>
    <string name="developedBy_For_Splash">By AgTrain Trading P.L.C</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="references_Title">References</string>
    <string name="references">Bargeron, C.T., J.H. LaForest, J. Brock, D.B. Langston &amp; R.L. David, B. Dutta. (2015).
        \n\nVegDr Android App. (Version 2.0) [Mobile application software]. Available at https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bugwood.
        \n\nvegetabledoctor Ravi Shankar, Seema Harsha &amp; Raj Bhandary (2014).
        \n\nA PRACTICAL GUIDE TO IDENTIFICATION AND CONTROL OF PEPPER DISEASES, TROPICA SEEDS PVT LTD R &amp; D department Bangalore 560004 INDIA
Ravi Shankar, Seema Harsha &amp; Raj Bhandary (2014).
        \n\nA PRACTICAL GUIDE TO IDENTIFICATION AND CONTROL OF TOMATO DISEASES, TROPICA SEEDS PVT LTD R &amp; D department Bangalore 560004 INDIA
\n\nTomato diseases Android App. (Version 2.1.5) [Mobile application software]. Available at https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Hazera. Tomato diseases
\n\nOnion diseases Android App. (Version 2.1.5) [Mobile application software]. Available at https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com. Hazera. Onion diseases
\n\nBrassica diseases Android App. (Version 2.1.5) [Mobile application software]. Available at https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com. Hazera. Brassica diseases
        \n\nCABBAGE BASIC PRODUCTION PRACTICES TECHNICAL BROCHURE and LEAF LET, SNV Netherlands Development organization
</string>

    <string name="title_activity_about_Agtrain_title">About AgTraIn</string>
    <string name="detailInfo_about_Agtrain">AgTraIn PLC (Agricultural Transformation by Innovation)
        is a privately owned Ethiopian Company registered in Ethiopia. The company is working mainly
        on developing and delivering technological products and services for the agricultural sector.\n
        The company focus on developing technological supporting tools for the two main farming components
        in the agricultural sector, smallholder farmers and export oriented farms. \n\nAgTraIn is working to
        support the existing extension service by developing offline mobile applications to support
        smallholder farmers. The present app is focusing on the Integrated Pest Management (IPM) practices
        of the pest, disease and disorders of most commonly growing 4 Vegetables. This will help farmers
        and extension agents to get timely advice by reading and comparing with the pictures. It helps
        them manage the risks accordingly and thereby  increase yield.
</string>

    <string name="title_activity_about_Agtrain">AgTraIn PLC (Agricultural Transformation by Innovation)
        is a privately owned Ethiopian Company registered in Ethiopia. The company is working mainly
        on developing and delivering technological products and services for the agricultural sector.
        The company focus on developing technological supporting tools for the two main farming components
        in the agricultural sector, smallholder farmers and export oriented farms. AgTraIn is working to
        support the existing extension service by developing offline mobile applications to support
        smallholder farmers. The present app is focusing on the Integrated Pest Management (IPM) practices
        of the pest, disease and disorders of most commonly growing 4 Vegetables. This will help farmers
        and extension agents to get timely advice by reading and comparing with the pictures. It will
        help to manage them accordingly so as to increase yield and be productivity. </string>

    <string name="title_activity_about_HortiLife_Title">About Horti-Life Project</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about_HortiLife">The Horti-LIFE project aim to address issues of low productivity
        and the high pressure from pests and diseases that horticultural smallholders are facing by
        establishing Farmer Field Schools (FFS) to capacitate smallholders to adapt Good Agricultural
        Practices (GAP) and Integrated Pest Management (IPM) practices in their horticultural production.
        \n\nThe reader of the provided INFORMATION in this current mobile application agrees that any
        risk of any kind from any use of the provided INFORMATION rests entirely and completely with
        the reader. \n\nIn no event will SNV Horti LIFE or its employees be liable for any damage or
        punitive damages arising out of the use of or inability to use the INFORMATION included in
        THE PRESENT mobile application. Prior to any use of data FROM THE PRESENT mobile application,
        you are advised to consult with your local experts, to verify and validate the applicability of
        the retrieved INFORMATION. There are no warranties as to the results obtained from the use of the
        information included in the PRESENT mobile application.
</string>

    <string name="title_activity_about">About</string>
    <string name="about_Title">Ethiopian Vegetable Insect Pests and Disease Guide</string>
    <string name="about_Detail_Information"><b>VegDr provides you information for vegetable pest, diseases
        and disorders.</b> The app includes 4 vegetable crops which Horti-LIFE project is
        working on (Onion, Pepper, Tomato and Cabbage). The app contains information on 20 pests\',
        35 diseases\', and 13 disorders\' images of the symptoms, IPM recommendations and lists
        products that are considered effective for control. \n\nRecommendations are based on information
        on the manufacturer\'s label and performance data from research and Extension trials from the
        Farmers Field School. \n\nVegDr is developed by AgTraIn PLC and funding provided by the Horti-LIFE
        project of SNV Netherlands Development Organization.
    </string>
    <string name="contact_info"><b>AgTraIn plc</b>,\t agtraintrading@gmail.com, info@agtraintrading.com.et, andnetbay@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Change Language</string>
    <string name="onion">Onion</string>
    <string name="onion_AMH">ሽንኩርት</string>
    <string name="cabbage">Cabbage</string>
    <string name="cabbage_AMH">ጥቅል ጎመን</string>
    <string name="tomato">Tomato</string>
    <string name="tomato_AMH">ቲማቲም</string>
    <string name="pepper">Pepper</string>
    <string name="pepper_AMH">ቃሪያ</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sub_menu">SubMenuActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cabbage__sub_menue">Cabbage_SubMenue</string>
    <string name="title_activity_problem_category">problems</string>
    <string name="category_Image_Description">categoryImageDescription</string>

    <string name="designed_and_Developed_by">Designed and Developed by AGTRAIN Trading</string>
    <string name="license_Information">License Information</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="choose_Language">Choose Language....</string>
    <string name="For_more_information">For more information, contact:</string>
    <string name="numberOfElement">available problem list = </string>
    <string name="title_activity_problem_sub_category">problem_subCategory</string>
    <string name="subCategory_Activity_Title">Problem List</string>
    <string name="subMenu_English">Main Title</string>
    <string name="subMenu_Amharic">ንዑስ ርዕስ</string>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <!-- Detail Information layout  Tab Information-->
    <string name="title_activity_detail__information">Detail Information</string>
    <string name="Tab_description">Description</string>
    <string name="Tab_Efficacy">Efficacy</string>
    <string name="Tab_PestControl_Recommendation">Product</string>
    <string name="Tab_ImageSymptoms">Images</string>

    <string name="cabbage_categoryTitle">Cabbage </string>
    <string name="onion_categoryTitle">Onion </string>
    <string name="Pepper_categoryTitle">Pepper </string>
    <string name="Tomato_categoryTitle">Tomato </string>
    <!-- Bullated_List-->
    <string name="bullted_list"><b><big>Bulleted List</big></b>
        \n <li>Item one</li>
        \n <li>Item two</li>
        \n <li>Item three</li>
    </string>

    <!-- Description Fragment-->
    <string name="problem_MainTitle"> Problem Main Title</string>
    <string name="problem_subTitle"> Problem sub Title</string>
    <string name="problem_Description">Detail information</string>
    <string name="recommendation_Title_Pest">Integrated Pest Management Recommendation</string>
    <string name="recommendation_Title1_Disease">Integrated Disease Management Recommendation</string>
    <string name="recommendation_Title1_Disorder">Recommendation</string>
    <string name="recommendation_Detail">Recommendation Detail Information</string>

    <!-- Efficacy Fragment -->
    <string name="efficacyTitle">List of Effective Products</string>

    <!-- Image Fragment -->
    <string name="imageInformation_Title">Image Information</string>
    <string name="com_google_android_gms_fonts_certs"> as</string>

    <string name="pestControl_RecommendationTitle">Pest Control Recommendation</string>
    <!-- Cabbage Detail Information English-->
    <string name="problemName"> </string>
    <string name="msg_no_product_found">
        There are no specific methods of control, so contact your local agronomist and try to control it by implementing better prevention and control methods.
    </string>

    <!-- Cabbage Detail Information English-->

    <!-- Disease -->
    <string name="Cabbage_Club_root_Title">Club Root</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Club_root">Club root of cabbage is caused by caused by the soil borne fungus
        Plasmodiophora brassicae. The ideal temperature for the fungus is between 13\u00B0 and 15\u00B0C. Club root
        mainly occur in acid and wet soil. Affected plants are wilting and turn from pale green to yellow on separated
        spots in the field. The fungus enters the plant through the roots, and makes root swell up. These roots will not function anymore.
        Spores of the disease are mainly spread by water and contaminated soil. Spores of the fungus can survive up to 7 years in the soil.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Club_root_IPM_Recomm">\nKeep the PH of the soil above 7, by limiting the soil and use drains to avoid wet spots.
        \nFertilize with calcium based nitrogen to stimulate the growth of new roots.
\nThere are resistant varieties available, but they do not bring total protection, because of the different strains of club root.
\nChoose resistant cultivars when possible.
\nTry to prevent the occurrence of this disease by keeping a clean garden and rotating crops.
\nKeep in mind that the disease spores can persist in the soil for up to 20 years. If club root is present you may want to solarize the soil
\nControl susceptible weeds mustard, radish, shepherd’s purse that may be infected to reduce potential buildup of the disease.
\nCarefully remove infected plants and sterilize garden tools (one part bleach to 4 parts water) after use
    </string>

    <!--Verticillium wilt-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Verticillium_wilt_Title">Verticillium Wilt</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Verticillium_wilt">Verticillium dahliae is a fungal plant pathogen. It causes
        vascular wilt of Brassica and many plant species, causing leaves to curl and discolor. Verticillium
        develops under cool conditions (15\u00B0-19\u00B0C). This disease causes V-Shaped lesions with yellow borders
        formed along the margins of the lower leaves. One sided discoloration on the leaf is possible.
        The vascular system of the infected plant will turn dark and brown. The fungus survives in the soil,
        continuous cropping will make the disease build up.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Verticillium_wilt_IPM_Recomm">A good crop rotation is very important to keep this disease from building up.\n
        Destroying all infected plants at the site as well as any susceptible weeds.\n
        Use of resistant cultivars is the most effective method for control of Verticillium wilt\n</string>

    <!-- Fusarium yellows-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Fusarium_Yellows_Title">Cabbage Fusarium Yellows</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Fusarium_Yellows">Fusarium yellows is a warm-weather disease caused by the soilborne
        fungus Fusarium oxysporum f. sp. conglutinans. The fungus is closely related to, but distinct from,
        fungi causing Fusarium wilts of melons, peas, pepper, potato, sweet potato, tomato, carnation,
        China aster, gladiolus, cotton, and numerous other plants. Fusarium yellow needs a soil
        temperature above 18\u00B0C to be active. Symptoms are yellowing leaves and wilting of the plants.
        The leaves of the plant will become twisted because of blocked vascular system. This blocking
        can be checking by cutting the stem of the plant, brown discoloration will be visible. Fusarium
        usually affect spots on the field. Spores of the fungus can survive in the soil for several years.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Fusarium_Yellows_IPM_Recomm">Resistant varieties are available and provided the most effective control.\n
Grow transplants in soil that has been disinfested by steam or a soil fumigant.\n
Rotate the field or garden to non-host crops such as lettuce, peppers, or tomatoes for several years to prevent buildup of the Fusarium fungus in the soil.\n
Purchase only certified, disease-free seed or transplants of resistant varieties.\n
Keep the fungus out of yellows-free fields and gardens by preventing the spread of infested soil carried on equipment, tools, feet, and running water.\n
Do not put crop debris in compost or manure piles.\n</string>

    <!-- Black leaf spots-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Black_leaf_spots_Title">Black Leaf Spots</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Black_leaf_spots">Alternaria Leaf Spot is a common disease of cabbage caused
        by the fungal pathogen Alternaria brassicicola. Alternaria prefers warm (20\u00B0-25\u00B0C) and humid conditions.
        Many black spots will appear on the leaves, stem veins and heads of the cabbage. The spores can survive
        on the crop residue and spread through wind, soil and water. The fungus can also infect seeds. The
        seedlings of contaminated seeds will die as a young plants.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Black_leaf_spots_IPM_Recomm">A clean start is important make sure that the seed are not contaminated.\n
Seed treatment can prevent the disease from spreading at a young stage.\n
A minimum two year crop rotation is recommended, alternating with non-cruciferous crops.\n
Elimination of crop residue are important in the prevention of the disease.\n</string>

    <!-- Light leaf spots-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Light_leaf_spots_Title">Light Leaf Spots</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Light_leaf_spots">Light leaf spots is caused by a plant pathogen Pyrenopeziza
        brassicae and infecting Brassicaceae family. Light leaf spots favors cool temperatures (16\u00B0C)
        and leaves and to be wet for at least 48 hours. The fungus can slow the development of the
        infected plant. Small irregular brown spots will form on infected part of the plant. There
        spots can tear open easily. Spores of the fungus appear together in a circle. Spores of the
        fungus can travel by wind, but they need water to enter the plant.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Light_leaf_spots_IPM_Recomm">It is important to clean the field of the plant debris after harvest to prevent light leaf spots from making spores.\n
Crop rotation can reduce the pressure of the disease.\n
Some varieties are more susceptible than others.\n</string>

    <!--Phytophthora-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Phytophthora_Title">Phytophthora</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Phytophthora">Phytophthora is a genus of plant-damaging oomycetes (water molds).
        Phytophthora prefers temperatures above 13\u00B0C and the presence of water on the field. Water is
        important for Phytophthora: the fungus travels through it and only affects plants at wet spots
        on the field. Usually plants which are weakened by flooding will be affected. Infected plants
        will wilt and eventually rot. The fungus enters the plants through the root system. The fungus
        produces spores which can survive in the soil.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Phytophthora_IPM_Recomm">Make sure there is a good structure and drainage available.\n
It is important the top layer of the soil does not get soaked.\n
A crop rotation of 3 years is advisable.\n</string>

    <!-- Black rot-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Black_Rot_Title">Black Rot</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Black_Rot">Black rot, caused by the bacterium Xanthomonas campestris pv. campestris,
        is considered the most serious disease. The bacterial development most quickly under hot >25\u00B0C and humid
        conditions. The infection starts at the stomata at the end of the leaf margins, hydathodes, with yellow to
        brown V-shaped lesions. Another symptom is blackening of veins. The disease spreads by soil, water, men,
        machinery and can be seed born.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Black_Rot_IPM_Recomm">There are no resistant varieties available, but there is big difference in susceptibility between varieties.\n
There is no chemical available for Black Rot.\n
Treatment with copper fungicides will keep the bacterial from spreading.\n
Do not enter infected fields in the morning when the plant is guttering, and remove weeds from the field, so they cannot act as a host.\n
Crop rotation of more than 4 years is recommended.\n</string>


    <!--Damping off-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Damping_Off_Title">Damping off</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Damping_Off">Damping off is caused by fungus or fungus-like microorganisms,
        Pythium spp., Phytophthora spp., Fusarium spp., Rhizoctonia solani, and other fungi. Affected
        plants usually occur in patches in nursery beds or in low parts of sloped fields. In level fields,
        affected plants are generally found in scattered areas. \nDamping off may occur before and/or
        after emergence. In pre-emergence damping off, the seeds fail to emerge after sowing. They become
        soft, mushy, turn brown, and decompose as a consequence of seed infection. In post-emergence
        damping-off, the seedling emerges from the soil but dies shortly afterwards. The affected portions
        (roots, hypocotyls and perhaps the crown of the plant) are pale brown, soft, water soaked, and
        thinner than non-affected tissue. Infected stems collapse. Stunting of plants due to root rot or
        collar rot may also occur.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Damping_Off_IPM_Recomm">use plug transplants and a soilless pathogen-free growth medium \n
Water seedlings only when the soil or growth medium is dry, preferably in the morning to allow drying to occur by the late afternoon.\n
Avoid contact with ground soil or other sources of contamination.\n
Choose well-drained locations and Keep the seedbed well ventilated and Sow on raised beds.\n
Avoid overcrowding of plants and the movement of infested soil or contaminated plant material into the nursery bed.\n
Workers should clean their hands and tools before handling healthy plants.\n
Surface irrigation ponds may be a source of fungal contamination.\n
Pots or transplant containers should be new or treated recently with a disinfectant (10% household bleach) or\n</string>

    <!-- Pests -->

    <!--Diamondback moth-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Diamondback_Moth_Title">Diamondback Moth</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Diamondback_Moth">The diamondback moth (Plutella xylostella), sometimes
        called the cabbage moth, is a moth species belonging to the family Plutellidae and genus
        Plutella. The small, grayish-brown moth sometimes has a cream-colored band that forms a
        diamond along its back. The insects feed on all crucifers; all parts above the ground can
        be eaten by the caterpillar. Mainly the leaves, but also growing points can be attacked.
        The adults lay groups of yellow eggs on the lower side of the leaves. The caterpillars from
        these eggs will cause the damage.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Diamondback_Moth_IPM_Recomm">It is important to prevent the adult from laying eggs to make sure there are no caterpillars in the crop.\n
Diamond black moth can be controlled both chemically and with Bacillus thuringiensis based products, the latter only work in warm conditions.\n</string>


    <!-- Thrips-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Thrips_Title">Thrips</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Thrips">Thrips angusticeps is an insect pest on crops of flax, cereals and
        peas and Onion Thrips Thripa tabaci. They are small (2mm) insect pests classified under Thysanoptera:
        Thripidae. Adult thrips are thin and small insect has light yellow to brown color slender insects
        with fringed wings. The larvae has similar appearance with very light color and no wings.
        The main damage from thrips is cosmetic. Thrips sting the cabbage and suck plant juice from
        cells. The damaged cell forms an oedema. This can lead to losses in storage cabbage. Thrips
        have a lot hosts (leek, onion, carrot, wheat and cabbage) and can overwinter. The pressure is
        highest in dry and hot conditions, because then the development from larvae to adult is a lot shorter.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Thrips_IPM_Recomm">Chemical control for thrips is possible, but difficult because the insect can hide between the layers of the cabbage\n
It is important to spray early in the morning or late in the evening when the insect is active.\n
There is a difference in susceptibility between varieties.\n</string>


    <!-- Cabbage Aphids-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Aphids_Title">Cabbage Aphids</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Aphids">Cabbage aphid or cabbage aphis, (Brevicoryne brassicae) are around
        2mm long and look gray-green covered with powdery substance. The aphids feed on many varieties
        of produce, including cabbage, broccoli (especially), Brussels sprouts, cauliflower and many
        other members of the genus Brassica, but do not feed on plants outside of the Brassicaceae family.
        They can reproduce very quickly and form colonies on the bottom of the leaves. Affected leaves
        will become rough, curly and purple. Aphids overwinter as eggs on crucifers, in spring they form
        the first generations. In September the first winged males will occur and start mating, the
        females then lay the eggs for overwintering.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Aphids_IPM_Recomm">Clear the field of plant debris and cruciferous weeds so the aphids have nowhere to overwinter.\n
Aphids can controlled chemically.\n</string>

    <!-- Cabbage Disorder-->

    <!-- Bolting-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Bolting_Title">Bolting</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Bolting">If the night temperatures are low, the plant will start to flower
        early and prematurely run to seed, usually making them unusable. Occurs in Broccoli, Brussels
        sprouts, Cauliflower, and Headed cabbage.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Bolting_IPM_Recomm">There is difference in susceptibility between varieties.\n
There are resistant varieties available.\n</string>

    <!-- Splitting, Cracking and doubling-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Splitting_Cracking_and_doubling_Title">Splitting, Cracking and Doubling</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Splitting_Cracking_and_doubling">Occurs in Broccoli, Cauliflower, and Headed cabbage.
        The curd of the cauliflower is cracked so the head becomes unmarketable. This disorder is caused by
        interrupted and too fast growth.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Splitting_Cracking_and_doubling_IPM_Recomm">Make sure the plant has a continuous growth.\n
There is a difference in susceptibility between varieties.\n</string>

    <!--Bracting-->
    <string name="Cabbage_Bracting_Title">Bracting</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Bracting">In broccoli and cauliflower. Covering leaves grow through the curd.
        This disorder is stress induced, the main causes of stress are high temperatures and lack of water.</string>
    <string name="Cabbage_Bracting_IPM_Recomm">There is a big difference in susceptibility between varieties.\n
Use varieties adapted to hot and dry conditions.\n</string>


    <!-- Onion Detail Information English -->

    <!-- Pests -->


    <!-- Thrips -->
    <string name="Thrips_Title">Thrips</string>
    <string name="Thrips_SubTitle">Thrips tabaci</string>
    <string name="Thrips">Onion Thrips are small (2mm) insect pests classified under Thysanoptera: Thripidae.
        Adult thrips are thin and small insect has light yellow to brown color slender insects with fringed wings.
        The larvae has similar appearance with very light color and no wings. These insects that feed on young
        leaves in the inner neck of the onion plants. In these areas, they damage the plants by rasping and
        piercing leaf cells. The population increases rapidly under hot and dry conditions they will be
        visible everywhere in the plant showing the leaf will damaged showing white spots and gradually
        changed to grayish white. Intensive feeding results in a silvery-white stippled appearance also
        referred to as white blast or silver top leave thin and twisted leaf. These insects is able to
        spread the Iris Yellow Spot Virus. Onion trips, Thrips tabaci, and the western flower thrips,
        Frankliniella occidentalis, are the two most important thrips in onions.</string>
    <string name="Thrips_IPM_Recommendation">Frequent Ploughing between 15 -20 days and exposing the soil to sun\n
    Avoid continuous onion planting on the same field\n
    Avoid cultivation of onions adjacent to fields of green, as green serves as a host crop for the onion thrips.\n
    Do not use excessive amount of nitrogen and dress it in multiple applications during the growth season.\n
    Use appropriate pesticides to control pest.\n</string>
    <string name="Thrips_Pesticide_Recommendation">To avoid resistance, Use chemicals under different chemical group\n
    ACTELIC 50% 500ml per 400 - 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    RADIANT / TRACER 200ml per 400 - 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    Additionally applying NEMBICIDINE EC, LAMDEX/ CARATE 5 EC, DECIS 2.5 SC, CONFIDOR SL/
        CONFIDENCE 350 SC will help to control the pest better.\n</string>

    <!-- Leaf Miner-->
    <string name="Leaf_Miner_Title">Leaf Miner</string>
    <string name="Leaf_Miner">Liriomyza huidobrensis, commonly known as the pea leaf miner, is a species
        of insect, a fly categorized under the order Diptera in the family Agromyzidae. The larvae of
        this fly mine the leaves and stems of peas and a range of other vegetables. On the leaves
        light-green to whitish meandering tunnels appear. These are caused by the larvae of small
        flies (leaf miners). When there is severe Punctures and mines, It will affect productivity
        and kill young plants. The maggot has a pale color and will only be found in the leaf mines.
        When fully grown it colors pale green or yellow. The pupa is black and can be seen in the tunnel.
        Flies are yellow and black colored.</string>
    <string name="Leaf_Miner_IPM_Recommendation">To break the life cycle of the pest, removing crop residue by burring or burning is important\n
    Clearing of volunteer crops (incl. weeds) that serve as a host to the leaf miner.\n
    Avoid continuous onion planting on the same field\n
    Use appropriate pesticides to control pest.\n</string>
    <string name="Leaf_Miner_Pesticide_Recommendation">To avoid resistance, Use chemicals under different chemical group\n
    ACTELIC 50% 500ml per 400 - 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    RADIANT / TRACER 200ml per 400 - 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    Additionally applying NEMBICIDINE EC, LAMDEX/ CARATE 5 EC, DECIS 2.5 SC, CONFIDOR SL/ CONFIDENCE 350 SC will help to control the pest better.\n
    </string>


    <!-- Disease-->
    <!-- Pink Root-->
    <string name="Pink_Root_Title">Pink Root</string>
    <string name="Pink_Root">Pink root of onion (Allium cepa) is caused by the soil borne pathogen
        Phoma terrestris.  High temperatures cause ideal circumstances for the development of Pink
        root in the soil. The fungus appears as a discoloration of the roots, which will color from
        light ping to yellow brown. Finally, roots will shrivel, become brittle and die. Optimal
        temperature for development: 25°C-28°C. </string>
    <string name="Pink_Root_IPM_Recommendation">Use varieties with resistance to Pink root.\n
        Solarization has proven effective in many areas.\n
        Crop rotation with non-host\n
        crops will decrease the chance of infection.\n
        It is common that is remains in the soil for >5 years.\n</string>
    <string name="Pink_Root_Pesticide_Recommendation">CHLOROPICRIN (various products) has
        been used as a soil fumigant since 1920. The primary use today is for preplant soil fumigation
        to control soil borne fungi, diseases and nematodes. Eg. Pink root\n</string>

    <!-- White Rot-->
    <string name="White_rot_Title">White rot</string>
    <string name="White_rot">White rot is caused by the soil-borne fungus Sclerotium cepivorum. It
        can infect all plants in the Allium family (including leeks and chives,) but garlic and
        onions are the most susceptible. The symptoms of white rot are yellow leaves and limited or
        no development of the canopy. Infected bulbs show white, thick and fluffy spots on the basal
        plate. The origin of this fungus are dark colored sclerotia, which can remain in the soil
        for a long period of time and often spread around by tillage of the soil. Optimum
        temperature for development: 15°C-20°C</string>
    <string name="White_rot_IPM_Recommendation">Prevent spreading of the spores by avoiding
        spreading of infected soil (clean machinery).\n
        Make sure non-infected plant material (sets or transplants).\n
        If possible, prevent the spread of irrigation water between healthy and infected fields. \n
    	Remove and destroy infected plants from the field.\n
    	Remove crop residues from the field and maintain a (very) wide crop rotation.\n
    	Register the location of the infected fields and follow-up.\n</string>
    <string name="White_Root_Pesticide_Recommendation">Three fungicides are commonly used for white rot control: tebuconazole, fludioxonil and boscalid.\n
    Regardless of which fungicide is used, they need to be applied in a 10 – 15 cm bandwidth, at planting, and in the seed furrow.\n
    Later fungicide applications are ineffective in controlling disease.\n
    Please note that tebuconazole is phytotoxic on onions if it is applied at a higher concentration than the recommended 1.5 liters per hectare.\n
    Phytotoxicity can also occur if the bandwidth is narrowed, even at the recommended rate per hectare.\n</string>


    <!-- Downy mildew-->

    <string name="Downly_Mildew_Title">Downy mildew</string>
    <string name="Downny_Mildew">Peronospora destructor is a plant pathogen. It causes downy mildew on
        leaves of cultivated and wild Allium. Allium cepa (onion and shallot) is most often affected,
        while Allium schoenoprasum (chives) and Allium porrum (leek) are only occasionally affected.
        Symptoms are mostly visible from the middle to the top of foliage, where light greenish to
        yellowish oval patches appear. On old leaves, thin grayish or purple color cotton like pathogen
        growth is first symptom. Finally, the leaf will fall down after the leaf changes its color gradually.
        High humidity combined with high temperatures will lead to a fast development and spread of the fungus.
        Optimal temperature for infection and development is 13°C and 22°C respectively.</string>
    <string name="Downy_Mildew_IPM_Recommendation">Choose a variety with high resistance level.\n
    Treat the seed with fungicide before seeding.\n
    Start cultivation with plants that are not infected with (set or transplants).\n
    Allow proper air circulation and reduce duration of leaf wetness.\n
    Remove crop residues from the field as they can lead to outbreaks.\n
    Maintain a crop rotation of minimal 5 years.\n
    If possible, apply an accurate and preventive spray management to control.\n</string>
    <string name="Downy_Mildew_Pesticide_Recommendation">Field monitoring and adequate diagnosis of diseases symptoms.\n
    Spray at the first sign of the disease to control the disease.\n
    Apply RIDOMIL GOLD anti fungus 1.5-2 Kg per 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    Apply MANCOZEB anti fungus 1.5-2 Kg per 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    Additionally applying CURAZATE RWP, FUNGURAN OK 50 WP, KOCIDE 2000 WDG, EQUATION PRO WDGs
        and NATIVE 300 SC will help to control the disease better.\n
    Depending on the temperature and humidity, repeat fungicide application every 7 - 14 days until harvesting.\n</string>


    <!-- Purple Blotch-->

    <string name="Purple_Blotch_Title">Purple Blotch</string>
    <string name="Purple_Blotch">Purple blotch is caused by the fungus Alternaria porri. It can infect
        all above ground parts of the plant in addition to the bulb. Seed borne pathogen transmits the disease.
        The leaves are showing small, water-soaked lesions with white centers. During further development of
        the fungus the lesions become bigger and ring with traces develop. The edges of the lesion color
        red-purplish, surrounded by a yellow zone. The dissemination of infestation will enforce the plant
        to easily broken down. Based on the level of infestation, diseased plants will die. High Relative
        humidity at night and long periods of wet leaves during the day are beneficial for the fungus.
        6\u00B0C to 34\u00B0C is optimal temperature for development of the fungus. This disease has similar
        symptoms as that of downy mildew. The preventive and controlling methods are similar.</string>
    <string name="Purple_Blotch_IPM_Recommendation">Choose a variety with high resistance level.\n
    Treat the seed with fungicide before seeding.\n
    Start cultivation with plants that are not infected with (set or transplants).\n
    Allow proper air circulation and reduce duration of leaf wetness.\n
    Remove crop residues from the field as they can lead to outbreaks.\n
    Maintain a crop rotation of minimal 5 years.\n
    If possible, apply an accurate and preventive spray management to control.\n</string>
    <string name="Purple_Blotch_Pesticide_Recommendation">Field monitoring and adequate diagnosis of diseases symptoms.\n
    Spray at the first sign of the disease to control the disease.\n
    Apply RIDOMIL GOLD anti fungus 1.5-2 Kg per 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    Apply MANCOZEB anti fungus 1.5-2 Kg per 600Lt of water per Ha\n
    Additionally applying CURAZATE RWP, FUNGURAN OK 50 WP, KOCIDE 2000 WDG, EQUATION PRO WDG\n
        and NATIVE 300 SC will help to control the disease better.
    Depending on the temperature and humidity, repeat fungicide application every 7 - 14 days until it reaches harvesting.\n</string>

    <!-- Onion Bacterial soft rot-->
    <string name="Onion_Bacterial_Soft_Rot_Title">Onion Bacterial Soft Rot</string>
    <string name="Onion_Bacterial_Soft_Rot">Erwinia carotovora bacteria commonly cause onion Bacterial
        Soft Rot. The bacteria infects through damages on the canopy, which may be the effect of hail,
        insects or fungi. Onion plants can be infected on the field. The rotting process starts in the
        center of the bulb, the structure of the onion breaks down. A yellow to brown slimy fluid can
        expose when pressure is applied to the base of the onion bulb. Infected bulbs have a foul-smelling
        odor. Most of the time, this disease can happen if the onion is stored without proper drying.</string>
    <string name="Onion_Bacterial_Soft_Rot_IPM_Recommendation">Select fields with a good structure and water management prior to onion cultivation.\n
    Use non-contaminated plant material.\n
    Avoid excessive use of nitrogen fertilizer.\n
    It can be possible to “roll the tops” mechanically to avoid improperly dried necks after storm or hail damages.\n
    Maintain cleaning to control insects and diseases.\n
    During harvesting protect diseases dissemination by removing the roots and the leaves\n
    Harvest at dry conditions after proper maturity period.\n
    Avoid mixing infected and non-infected onion during harvest\n
    It is good to properly dry the produce and avoid moisture during storage\n
    During storage, leave enough space for air circulation and ventilation to reduce moisture\n
    Avoid mechanical damage during harvest, selection, packaging, transportation and storage.\n</string>
    <string name="Onion_Bacterial_Soft_Rot_Pesticide_Recommendation">Copper bactericides provide bacterial control when applied before disease is observed.\n
    Depending on weather conditions, Sprays should be initiated two weeks before bulb initiation, and continued on a 5 to 10 days spray interval.\n
    Apply in a sufficient volume of water to ensure thorough coverage. Include a low rate of a non-ionic surfactant to further improve coverage.\n
    Sometimes, Copper tolerant strains of the pathogens are common. For this, Tank mixing copper bactericides (eg. Maneb) is essential for effective disease suppression.\n
    Tank-mixing coppers with zinc or iron can also enhance their activity.\n</string>
    <!--<string name="title_activity_home_page__land_scape_">HomePage_LandScape_Activity</string>-->

    <!-- Disorder-->
    <!-- Bolting-->
    <string name="Onion_Bolting_Title">Bolting</string>
    <string name="Onion_Bolting">The plant will start to reproduce and will form a flower head.
            This symptom is mostly caused by temperature changes (relative low temperatures) or other
            stress issues (e.g. damage). Bolters can rot away in storage. The onion plant is most
            sensitive to bolting when it has 2-3 real leaves and temperatures are low.</string>
    <string name="Onion_Bolting_IPM_Recommendation">Make us of varieties that are more tolerant to bolting.\n
            Avoid areas with cool climates at the start of the season.\n
            Certain temperature is needed to get bulb induction instead of bolting (depending on the area).\n</string>

    <!-- Splitting, Cracking and Doubling-->
    <string name="Onion_Splitting_Cracking_Title">Splitting, Cracking and Doubling</string>
    <string name="Onion_Splitting_Cracking">These three disorders are mostly caused by stress.
            The stress can be the outcome of excessive use of irrigation of fertilizers.
            Cracking will also appear when the onion experiences a growth stagnation followed by a
            growth explosion. This is for example visible after a long dry start followed by a long
            period of heavy rainfall.</string>
    <string name="Onion_Spliting_Cracking_IPM_Recommendation">To avoid this choice, Plant seed that is known to be free of genetic abnormalities.\n
            Apply the appropriate dosage of irrigation, fertilization and chemicals in order to avoid stress.\n
            A good soil structure will be beneficial for a uniform growth of the crop and will avoid stress conditions.\n</string>
    <!-- Chimera-->
    <string name="Onion_Chimera_Title">Chimera</string>
    <string name="Onion_Chimera">This is a genetic abnormality and its expression and occurrence is
        unaffected by environmental conditions. This condition generally occurs on only a small percentage
        of the plants in a field. The leaves of the onion are partly covered with yellow or light green
        stripes. This stripe is not covering the whole leaf in the width, but in the length. Variegated
        tissue patterns may be mosaic or linear. Leaf tissue is variegated resulting in tissues that have
        a normal green color being directly adjacent to tissues that are varying shades of yellow to white
        in color. Expression of chimera can be confused with a virus, but a chimera occurs in many cases
        in an individual plant.</string>
    <string name="Onion_Chimera_Recommendation">To avoid this disorder, Plant seed that is known to be free of genetic abnormalities.\n</string>


    <!-- Pepper -->

    <!-- Pests-->

    <!-- Boll Worm-->
    <string name="Pepper_Bollworm_Title">Boll Worm</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Bollworm">African boll worm is a species of moth in the Lepidoptera order of
        the family Noctuidae. It is a major pest in cotton and one of the most polyphagous and cosmopolitan
        pest species. African boll worm caterpillar is initially pale green, sometimes with black dots,
        and a pattern of thin dark lines running along the body, the lines being darker around the second
        and third segments. The severity of the damage varies between crops, regions and locations,
        and between seasons. Caterpillars of the African bollworm feed on leaves, buds, growing points,
        flowers and fruit. Leaf damage reduces leaf area, which can slow plant growth. Feeding on flowers
        and fruit causes the main damage. Flower feeding can prevent fruit formation. Caterpillars usually
        bore clean, circular holes through fruits/pods. Excrements (faeces / waste) of the feeding caterpillars
        are placed away from damaged plant parts. The holes serve as entry points for secondary infection
        by diseases causing fruit decay. One caterpillar can damage several fruits/pods. Once they burrow
        into the fruits/pods they are difficult to reach and to control with insecticides.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Bollworm_IPM_Recomm">Adequate identification/monitoring of different life stages and damage symptoms\n
Monitoring (field inspection, use of pheromone traps, etc), use a trap crop (e.g. African marigold) planted every 8 rows\n
Remove and destroy infected fruit and infested plants after harvest (burn or make compost)\n
Plough soil after harvesting to expose pupae to sunlight and natural enemies.\n
Allow natural enemies to flourish and Conserve natural enemies (Trichogramma pertiosum or T. achaeae, Macrolophus pygmaeus)\n
</string>

    <!-- Vegetable leaf miner-->
    <string name="Pepper_Vegetable_Leaf_Miner_Title">Vegetable Leaf Miner</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Vegetable_Leaf_Miner">Liriomyza huidobrensis, commonly known as the pea leaf
        miner, is a species of insect, a fly categorized under the order Diptera in the family Agromyzidae.
        The larvae of this fly mine the leaves and stems of peas and a range of other vegetables. On the
        leaves light-green to whitish meandering tunnels appear. These are caused by the larvae of small
        flies (leaf miners). When there is severe Punctures and mines, it will affect productivity and kill
        young plants. The maggot has a pale color and will only be found in the leaf mines. When fully
        grown it colors pale green or yellow. The pupa is black and can be seen in the tunnel. Flies are
        yellow and black colored.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Vegetable_Leaf_Miner_IPM_Recomm">To break the life cycle of the pest, removing crop residue by burring or burning is important\n
Clearing of volunteer crops (incl. weeds) that serve as a host to the leaf miner.\n
Avoid continuous onion planting on the same field\n
Use appropriate pesticides to control pest.\n
</string>

    <!-- Aphids-->
    <string name="Pepper_Aphids_Title">Aphids</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Aphids">Aphids are small sap-sucking insects and members of the superfamily
        Aphidoidea. Common names include greenfly and blackfly, although individuals within a species
        can vary widely in colour. They are soft bodied, bear shaped insects with a pair of dark cornicles
        and a cauda protruding from the pair of dark cornicles and a cauda protruding from the abdomen.
        They may be winged or wingless. The wingless form is most common. Aphids feed in colonies,
        causing discoloration or mottling of the foliage. They excrete honeydew on which sooty mold
        grows: Nymphs molt by shedding skin a few times before becoming an adult.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Aphids_IPM_Recomm">If infestation is minimal, use physical method and remove infected parts of the plants.\n
Biological control may be used by promoting natural enemies by applying selected pesticide\n
Use selected pesticide, please consult your local specialist.\n
</string>

    <!--White fly-->
    <string name="Pepper_White_fly_Title">White fly</string>
    <string name="Pepper_White_fly">Whiteflies Bemisia tabaci are small Hemipterans that typically feed
        on the undersides of plant leaves. Bemisia tabaci, the only vector of Tomato yellow leaf curl
        virus (TYLCV), has a very wide host range and is difficult to manage with insecticides. Bemisia tabaci
        is a serious pest in many vegetables including cucurbits, capsicums, capsicums, tomato, eggplant, brassicas
        lettuce, sweet potato and beans.\n\nWhiteflies are soft – bodies, yellow to clear (wingless juveniles)
        or white (winged adult) sap sucking insects. The insect has a high reproduction rate and a short
        generation time. Temperatures of between 25\u00B0C and 30\u00B0C are ideal for B. tabaci development. Whitefly
        lifecycle takes 18 to 28 days in warm weather and 30 to 48 days in cold weather. B. tabaci acquires
        TYLCV while feeding and sucking sap from the phloem tissue of virus – infected plants.\n\nAn adult
        B. tabaci needs to feed on an infected plant for at least 15 to 30 minutes to acquire the virus.
        After B. tabaci acquires TYLCV, there is a period of 6 to 24 hours before the insect can transmit
        the virus. This is called a latent period, after which adults are generally able to transmit TYLCV
        for life. Whiteflies are efficient vectors of TYLCV transmitting the virus following a single 15 to
        30 minutes feeding period. The insect pest will Secret honeydew encourages black sooty mold growth.
        Interferes with the photosynthesis and reduce vigorousity of plant and gradually will die.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_White_fly_IPM_Recomm">The use of registered insecticides to control whiteflies is also an important tool in reducing the spread of TYLCV.\n
However, this should not be the sole basis of TYLCV control as whiteflies have the ability to quickly develop resistance to insecticides.\n
Repetitive and frequent use of insecticides to control whiteflies may result in outbreaks of secondary pest such as tow spotted mite and leafminers.\n
A number of insecticides are effective against whitefly but it is important to understand the mode of action for each chemical so that it can be applied correctly.\n
In general, the most important aspects of spraying are as follows:\n
Check crops for whitefly regularly using a scouting method. Walking through a crop and inspecting it for any unusual outbreaks is very important.\n
Don’t continue to spray an insecticide if it is obviously not working as this leads to resistance.\n
Rotation of chemical mode of action groups is very important to prevent resistance from developing. Please also consult with your local specialist.\n</string>

    <!--Thrips -->
    <string name="Pepper_Thrips_Title">Thrips</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Thrips">The onion thrips, Thrips tabaci, are very small, from 0.5 to 1.2 mm
        at the immature stage to 2 mm at the immature stage to 2 mm for the adults is classified under
        Thysanoptera: Thripidae. The form of the thrips body is elongated, elliptical and slender. The
        eyes have a darker coloration and are easy to see. Immature thrips range from white to pale
        yellow and have short antennas. The difference between immature and adults is that immature do
        not have wings, so they cannot fly, and the adults are darker colure, from yellow to dark brown.
        \n\nThrips are thought to have originated in the eastern Mediterranean, but are now cosmopolitan.
        They prefer warm and dry environments and have a wide host range, including onion, garlic, leek,
        cucumber, cabbage, bedding plants, potato, melon, tomato, sugar beet, and weedy grasses. T.
        tabaci primarily feeds on conditions. It typically overwinters in small grains, clover, and
        alfalfa. Virus transmission may differ based on thrips gender, virus isolate, and source plant
        of virus. The onion thrips (Thrips tabaci) and Western flower thrips (Frankliniella occidentalis)
        are the main thrips types attacking vegetables.
</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Thrips_IPM_Recomm">The most effective management strategies rely on exclusion of infected plants and vector thrips.\n
Blue or yellow sticky cards are attractive to thrips, and are useful for monitoring populations.\n
Removal of infected (or suspected plants is crucial, as is control of weeds that may harbor the virus or thrips.\n
Reflective mulches have been demonstrated to reduce spread of TSWV in some systems (they are thought to cause confusion in thrips).\n
Contact insecticides are often not effective against thrips due to oviposition in tissue, the presence of adults inside tight buds and migration from surrounding plants.\n
Systemic insecticides often do not kill thrips fast enough to slow epidemics.\n
Many thrips biotypes exist with resistance to one or more insecticides, rotation of chemicals is vital to management.\n
Please consult your local supplier.\n
</string>

    <!--Cutworm-->
    <string name="Pepper_Cutworm_Title">Cutworm</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Cutworm">Cutworm, Peridroma saucia, the pearly underwing or variegated cutworm,
        is a species of moth of the family Noctuidae. Fat, basically gray, brown, or black caterpillar
        that is 40 to 50 mm long when full grown. It has 3 pairs of legs near the head and 5 pairs of
        fleshy prologs. Cutworms are active at night, young caterpillars climb on leaves, and the older
        caterpillar severs seedling stems near the ground. Cutworms hide during the day in soil burrows
        at the bases of plants.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Cutworm_IPM_Recomm">Destroy plat residues by tilling before plantation, especially when tomatoes follow a good host crop for cutworms (e.g. alfalfa or beans and cover crops that include legumes).\n
Manage weeds surrounding the field before planting.\n
Kill and till under or remove weeds, as cutworms will shelter in living and dead weeds.\n
If pupae are overwintering, only getting rid of host plants may not prevent damage.\n
During the season monitor the ground to detect damage.\n</string>

    <!--Broad mite-->
    <string name="Pepper_Broad_mite_Title">Broad Mite</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Broad_mite">Broad Mite, Polyphagotarsonemus latus Mites are nearly impossible
        to see without a hand lens. Females are nearly 0.2mm in length while males are 0.1mm long.
        Their eight-legged bodies are swollen ovals that can be amber, yellow, or green. The hind most
        legs in females are much reduced while enlarged in males. Eggs are colorless ellipses with tiny
        microscopic tufts that give them a speckled appearance. Immature mites are flattened, have only
        6 legs (at the earliest stage), and are slow moving.  Quiescent nymphs appear bloated, immobile,
        and pointed at each end.\n\nFeeding of broad mites causes malformations in young leaves and flower
        buds, stunted growth, drooping leaves, plant fragility, discolored fruit, and coppering or purpling
        leaves.  In some cases, severe mite infestations can lead to premature fruit drop and even plant
        death. Overall plant health and quality is significantly diminished due to the toxins found in
        broad mite saliva.\n\nBroad mites are pests on many fruit, vegetable, and ornamental crops
        throughout the tropics. Like other pests they can also be found in greenhouses at temperate
        regions. Some hosts are pepper, citrus, avocado, guava, and cotton.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Broad_mite_IPM_Recomm">Regularly inspect plants and disinfest of infested plants.\n
Establish new plantings from mite-free stock and never plant new plants near infested ones.\n
Predatory mites and six spotted thrips may help limit populations.\n
Met 52: Metarhizium anisopliae Strain F52. Growers in California have found Met52 to be an effective biological control for broad mites. The label rate is 560 - 4483 ml/Ha with a 0-day PHI\n
</string>


    <!--Disease-->
    <!--Bacterial Leaf Spot-->
    <string name="Pepper_Bacterial_Leaf_Spot_Title">Bacterial Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Bacterial_Leaf_Spot">Bacterial spot is caused by the Bacterium xanthomonas
        campestris pv. Vesicatoria. Bacterial spot is one of the most dangerous tomato diseases in
        existence, since it spreads rapidly and is very difficult to control. It infects both tomato
        and pepper. Spots that appear on leaves and stems are small (0.30 cm across), circular to irregular
        in shape, and have a slightly greasy feel. Unlike similar sized spots caused by the fungus
        septoria lycopersici, those caused by the bacterial spot pathogen do not develop grayish brown
        centers. As lesions enlarge, they often become surrounded by a yellow halo. If spots are numerous,
        they begin to grow together, and leaves wither and turn brown.\n\nFruit symptoms are more
        distinctive than leaf or stem symptoms. Spots on green fruit first appear as black, raised,
        pimple – like dots surrounded by water soaked areas. As the spots enlarge to 0.6 to 1.3 cm,
        they become gray – brown and scabby with sunken pitted centers. The bacterium overwinters on
        the surface of seeds, in infected debris, and in soil. It is commonly brought into fields on
        infected transplants. Warm rainy weather favors rapid spread of bacterial spot.
</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Bacterial_Leaf_Spot_IPM_Recomm">To control bacterial spot, a combination of cultural practices is often needed. These practices, which also will help to reduce the risk of many other diseases, include the following:
A combination of cultural practices is often needed to control bacterial spot and many other diseases.\n
Plant disease free transplants far enough apart so that the plants will not be crowded after they are fully grown, in order to help the foliage dry rapidly by good ventilation.\n
Water at the base of the plants, and in the morning rather than the evening, to minimize the amount of time that the leaves are wet.\n
Remove as much plant debris as possible in the fall and promptly plow under or bury the reaming residue.\n
Rotate crops so that tomatoes are grown in the same ground only three or four years.\n
Avoid working with plants when foliage is wet to avoid spreading disease – causing micro- organisms.\n
When the disease appears, change from overhead sprinkler to furrow irrigation\n
Destroying weeds around a tomato field or garden will help to reduce survival of the causal bacterium.\n
Fungicides also can help to control this disease.\n
A fixed copper product can help control spread of bacterial speck if applications begin when the first symptoms appear.\n
</string>

    <!--Fusarium stem and root rot-->
    <string name="Pepper_Fusarium_stem_and_root_rot_Title">Fusarium stem and root rot</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Fusarium_stem_and_root_rot">Fusarium root rot is caused primarily by the
        ascomycete fungus Fusarium solani. Fusarium solani has a very broad host range, causing primarily
        root rots, stem cankers, and damping off in plant species across many plant families. Soft, dark
        brown or black cankers are formed on the stem, usually at nodes or wound sites. These may girdle
        the stem in later stages of disease development. There is a dark brown discoloration of the
        internal portion of the stem that may extend a considerable distance. The lesions may eventually
        develop cinnamon or light orange-colored. Stem cankers restrict the upward flow of water resulting
        in wilting and death of the plant.\n\nThe ascospore germination occurs during prolonged periods
        of high humidity (ie. greater than 95%). A slow temperature increase early in the morning of 1°C
        per hour ensures that fruit and stem temperatures reach daytime targets before sunrise. Also,
        if the greenhouse has restricted ventilation and poor drainage, this may create a "wet" climate
        that N. haematococca can exploit for ascospore germination. Perithecia present on rockwool blocks
        and on fruit lesions provide further aerial inoculum which, when accompanied by a "wet" greenhouse
        climate, result in numerous fruit and stem infections. Other factors, such as over-watering of
        the rockwool blocks, can stress the plants through oxygen depletion, resulting in a high
        incidence of crown lesions.
</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Fusarium_stem_and_root_rot_IPM_Recomm">Do not allow rockwool blocks to dry out at the top because damaging levels of evaporated fertilizer salts may accumulate around the stem base and thus favour infection.\n
Avoid dripping fertilizer solution at the stem base by positioning the dripper away from the stem base.\n
Avoid excessively high fertilizer concentrations that contribute to salt damage.\n
Avoid overlap of crop production since the airborne spores of Nectria haematococca could be spread from the old crop to the early seeded peppers.\n
Seedling root dip treatment of bio control agents like Trichoderma viridae or Trichoderma harzianum during transplanting (10g/1litre of water)\n
</string>

    <!--Phytophora blight of pepper-->
    <string name="Pepper_Phytophora_blight_of_pepper_Title">Phytophora blight of pepper</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Phytophora_blight_of_pepper">Phytophthora blight of pepper is caused by the
        fungus Phytophthora capsici. Phytophthora blight of peppers can attack the roots, stems, leaves,
        and fruit, depending upon which stage plants are infected. The disease is most likely to occur
        at the soil line or on the lower 30 to 45 cm of the plant where water often pools or splashes.
        The most common symptoms regardless of the host plant are crown rot and fruit rot. On peppers,
        the disease causes a black lesion just above the soil line. Affected plants wilt and progressively
        die. Foliar lesions are less common, but can occur, especially when conditions are particularly
        favorable. The classic leaf lesion caused by P. capsici is fairly circular with a tan margin
        and brown, necrotic center.\n\nThe disease is favored by warm, wet weather and is polycyclic
        within seasons. The pathogen may survive as overwintering spores in the soil for many months
        and serve as inoculum or in infected plant tissues. Fruits in contact with the soil are most
        prone to infection. Sporangia/spores are easily dispersed by wind and rain splashes to leaves
        and stems of healthy plants. Excess soil moisture due to excess rain or irrigation, and soil
        temperature of 18°C–30°C arising from high air temperature are needed for disease development.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Phytophora_blight_of_pepper_IPM_Recomm">Rotate away from susceptible crops for a minimum of two years, preferably four years.\n
Grain crops are most suitable (e.g., corn and small grains) but crucifers are also good options.\n
Avoid poorly drained soils and low lying areas; If not create drainage ditches to ensure maximum soil-surface drainage from furrows;\n
Avoid excessive overhead irrigation;\n
Break up hardpans and plow-pans by subsoiling to increase soil drainage;\n
Enter infested fields last and clean equipment before moving to other fields\n
</string>

    <!--Powdery mildew-->
    <string name="Pepper_Powdery_mildew_Title">Powdery Mildew</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Powdery_mildew">Powdery mildew is caused by funguses Oidium neolycopersici
        or Leveillula taurica. It causes severe white powder on all aerial parts of tomato, excluding
        the fruit. Leaf symptoms of Oidiopsis taurica consist of yellow blotches or spots on the upper
        leaf surface. A white powdery growth occurs on the underside of the leaves. This fungus penetrates
        within the leaf tissue. For Oidium neolycopersici, symptoms first appear as small, powdery white
        colonies on the upper surface of the leaves. The fungal growth does not penetrate deeply into
        the leaf. The lower surface of the foliage may also be affected during later stages when the
        disease is severe .With both pathogens, the older colonies of the fungus may turn a dirty white
        colour with age. The severely affected leaves turn yellow, then brown, and later become shriveled.
        Generally, the lower leaves are affected first and the disease gradually moves up the plant.
        \n\nBoth fungi are prolific producers of spores that are readily dispersed by wind and rain.
        Many cycles of disease development occur during the plant’s growing period. The fungus spore
        is also spread by insect pests (thrips, aphids and whiteflies) and field workers, but to a
        lesser extent. The fungus is not seed borne. Spore germination and infection are favored by
        wide fluctuations of temperature and humidity during the day and night, which create periods
        of leaf wetness. O. taurica is favored by high relative humidity (greater than 85%) at night
        followed by warm (25° C), less humid conditions during the day. For O. neolycopersici, optimum
        disease development occurs at 22 °C particularly after 16 or 24 hours of leaf wetness;
        symptoms can appear within 7 days from the time that the spore lands on the leaf surface.
</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Powdery_mildew_IPM_Recomm">Avoid high rates of nitrogen, which make plants more susceptible to infection.\n
Avoid crowding and shading, which lead to the development of leaf wetness and conditions that promote infection.\n
Avoid overhead irrigation for the same reason.\n
Avoid planting young tomato plants while diseased plants remain nearby.\n
Control weeds around the planting site since both fungi have a wide host range and could persist on these plants during the growing season or during the off-season.\n
</string>

    <!--Root knot-->
    <string name="Pepper_Root_knot_Title">Root knot</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Root_knot">The root-knot nematode (Meloidogyne spp.) is a major plant pathogen,
        affecting several solanaceous crops worldwide. Nematode infestations damage the plant roots,
        and therefore symptoms reflect poorly functioning root systems. Above ground symptoms of severe
        root knot and stubby root nematode infestations include patches of chlorotic, stunted, necrotic,
        or wilted plants. Plants appear sluggish and appear off color even though adequate nutrition
        is provided. When infected plants are pulled up, roots are “knotted” and swollen with growths
        which may resulting a matted root system in severe cases.\n\nNematode-infested plants are more
        susceptible to moisture or temperature stress and exhibit stress symptoms earlier than other
        plants. Furthermore, root systems that have been damaged by nematodes are often more susceptible
        to infection by soil-inhabiting fungi such as Fusarium and Verticillium species.\n\nFeeding by
        root knot nematodes results in characteristic galls on roots. Severely galled roots may appear
        malformed and the root system shortened and thickened. In general, lighter, sandy soils favor
        nematode infection and result in more severe damage to roots.
</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Root_knot_IPM_Recomm">In fields infested with root knot nematodes, crop rotation may not be feasible because of their extensive host range;\n
Care is needed in the selection of rotation crops because some may be good alternate hosts.\n
Alternation with a ”trap crop” such as Elbon cereal rye which limits nematode reproduction may be effective.\n
It is advisable to plant resistant varieties, and many resistant varieties are available.\n
Soil solarization may help to lower the nematodes in the top layers of the soil and avoid an early infestation of the plants.\n
Roots are likely to become infested as the season progresses by nematodes that survived in the deeper soil layers.\n
</string>

    <!-- Pepper -->
    <!-- Disorder-->

    <!-- Blossom end rot-->
    <string name="Pepper_Blossom_end_rot_Title">Blossom end rot of Pepper</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Blossom_end_rot">Blossom-end rot is caused by a calcium deficiency in the developing
        fruit. This problem results from low levels of calcium in the soil or from a lack of soil moisture.
        Uptake of calcium from the soil depends on adequate moisture moving into the roots. Any condition
        that reduces roots’ ability to absorb water, and hence, take up calcium, can cause blossom-end
        rot. Heavy fertilization, resulting in an accumulation of ammonium, potassium, sodium or magnesium
        salts in the root zone, often increases the incidence of blossom-end rot by reducing calcium uptake.
        Also, excessive vegetative growth demands calcium, and may divert it away for the fruit.\n\nBlossom-end
        rot begins as a light-coloured area on the blossom end of the fruit. The affected area enlarges
        and darkens, sometimes involving up to half the fruit surface. On peppers, the rot is tan and may
        be mistaken for sun scald. Sun scald, however, results in a bleached, white area on the fruit.
        On bell pepper, the rot usually occurs on the tip of the lobes. Secondary fungi may cause the
        tan area to turn dark.</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Blossom_end_rot_IPM_Recomm">Applying lime or gypsum can provide calcium.\n
Lime corrects both low pH and low calcium levels, while gypsum only affects calcium level.\n
Calcium chloride sprays applied to the foliage may help prevent blossom-end rot on developing fruit.\n
Avoid excessive rates of ammonical nitrogen fertilizer.\n
Damage to the roots by deep cultivation should also be avoided, especially after fruit set and in dry weather\n
</string>

    <!--Sunscald-->
    <string name="Pepper_Sunscald_Title">Sunscald</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Sunscald">Bell pepper is a crop that requires high temperatures for growth.
        The hot weather and sunny days have been very beneficial for bell peppers growth and development.
        However, the fruit is very susceptible to sunburn (sunscald) under conditions of high
        irradiance.\n\nFruit exposed to the sun become extremely hot, in contrast to fruit protected
        by a dense canopy. The combination of hot weather and rain events increased the rate of fruit
        expansion, making fruit even more susceptible to sunburn. Additionally, sun damage makes the
        fruit vulnerable to plant pathogens. Growers will likely see significant crop losses from
        sunscald in peppers. In hot and sunny days, 10 to 29 % losses observed because of sunscald.
</string>
    <string name="Pepper_Sunscald_IPM_Recomm">Nutrient management prior to fruit set and during fruit set is critical.\n
Plants under poor soil fertility or drought stress develop a thin canopy with most of their fruit exposed\n
Adequate crop fertilization and irrigation help develop a thick canopy that protects fruit from direct sun.\n
Shading is the best management option; cultivars with a thick canopy usually show low sunscald incidence.\n
The harvest crew should be educated on the benefit of shading and how this reduces the incidence of sun scalding.\n
Crews should try, as much as possible, to avoid exposing immature fruit during harvest.\n
</string>


    <!-- Tomato -->

    <!-- Pests-->
    <!-- Vegetable leaf miner -->

    <string name="Tomato_Vegetable_leaf_Miner_Title">Vegetable Leaf Miner</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Vegetable_leaf_Miner">Vegetable leaf miner, Liriomyza sativae is a species of insect,
        a fly in the family Agromyzidae. The larvae of this fly mine the leaves of a range of vegetables and weeds,
        but seem to favour plants in the families Cucurbitaceae, Fabaceae and Solanaceae. Colorless to bright
        yellow maggot, up to 3mm long, with pointed head; makes serpentine mines in leaves; each mine slightly
        enlarged at one end. The adult will mine a hole for feeding and oviposition. On the leaves light-green
        to whitish meandering tunnels appear. These are caused by the larvae of small flies (leaf miners).
        When there is severe Punctures and mines, it will affect productivity and kill young plants.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Vegetable_Leaf_Miner_IPM_Recomm">The most important aspect of leaf miner management is conserving their natural enemies, which are often killed by broad-spectrum insecticides applied for other crop pests.\n
Reduce the risk of leaf miner outbreaks by applying insecticides for fruit pests only when monitoring shows treatment is needed and by choosing insecticides that are least likely to harm leaf miner parasites.\n</string>

    <!-- Aphids-->
    <string name="Tomato_Aphids_Title">Aphids</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Aphids">Aphids are small sap-sucking insects and members of the superfamily Aphidoidea.
        Common names include greenfly and blackfly, although individuals within a species can vary widely in colour.
        They are soft bodied, bear shaped insects with a pair of dark cornicles and a cauda protruding from the pair
        of dark cornicles and a cauda protruding from the abdomen. They may be winged or wingless. The wingless form
        is most common. Aphids feed in colonies, causing discoloration or mottling of the foliage.
        They excrete honeydew on which sooty mold grows: Nymphs molt by shedding skin a few times before becoming an adult.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Aphids_IPM_Recomm">If infestation is minimal, use physical method and remove infected parts of the plants.\n
Biological control may be used by promoting natural enemies by applying selected pesticide\n
Use selected pesticide, please consult your local specialist.\n</string>

    <!-- White Fly -->
    <string name="Tomato_White_Fly_Title">White Fly</string>
    <string name="Tomato_White_Fly">Whiteflies Bemisia tabaci are small Hemipterans that typically feed on the
        undersides of plant leaves. Bemisia tabaci, the only vector of Tomato yellow leaf curl virus (TYLCV),
        has a very wide host range and is difficult to manage with insecticides. Bemisia tabaci is a serious
        pest in many vegetables including cucurbits, capsicums, capsicums, tomato, eggplant, brassicas lettuce,
        sweet potato and beans. \nWhiteflies are soft – bodies, yellow to clear (wingless juveniles) or
        white (winged adult) sap sucking insects. The insect has a high reproduction rate and a short generation time.
        Temperatures of between 25\u00B0C and 30\u00B0C are ideal for B. tabaci development. Whitefly lifecycle takes 18 to 28 days
        in warm weather and 30 to 48 days in cold weather. B. tabaci acquires TYLCV while feeding and sucking sap from the
        phloem tissue of virus – infected plants. \nAn adult B. tabaci needs to feed on an infected plant for at least 15 to 30
        minutes to acquire the virus. After B. tabaci acquires TYLCV, there is a period of 6 to 24 hours before the insect can
        transmit the virus. This is called a latent period, after which adults are generally able to transmit TYLCV for life.
        Whiteflies are efficient vectors of TYLCV transmitting the virus following a single 15 to 30 minutes feeding period.
        The insect pest will Secret honeydew encourages black sooty mold growth. Interferes with the photosynthesis and reduce
        vigorousity of plant and gradually will die.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_White_Fly_IPM_Recomm">The use of registered insecticides to control whiteflies is also an important tool in reducing the spread of TYLCV.\n
However, this should not be the sole basis of TYLCV control as whiteflies have the ability to quickly develop resistance to insecticides.\n
Repetitive and frequent use of insecticides to control whiteflies may result in outbreaks of secondary pest such as tow spotted mite and leafminers.\n
A number of insecticides are effective against whitefly but it is important to understand the mode of action for each chemical so that it can be applied correctly.\n
In general, the most important aspects of spraying are as follows:\n
Check crops for whitefly regularly using a scouting method. Walking through a crop and inspecting it for any unusual outbreaks is very important.\n
Don’t continue to spray an insecticide if it is obviously not working as this leads to resistance.\n
Rotation of chemical mode of action groups is very important to prevent resistance from developing. Please also consult with your local specialist.\n</string>

    <!-- Thrips -->
    <string name="Tomato_Thrips_Title">Thrips</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Thrips">The onion thrips, Thrips tabaci, are very small, from 0.5 to 1.2 mm at
        the immature stage to 2 mm at the immature stage to 2 mm for the adults is classified under
        Thysanoptera: Thripidae. The form of the thrips body is elongated, elliptical and slender.
        The eyes have a darker coloration and are easy to see. Immature thrips range from white to pale
        yellow and have short antennas. The difference between immature and adults is that immature do not
        have wings, so they cannot fly, and the adults are darker colure, from yellow to dark brown.
        Thrips are thought to have originated in the eastern Mediterranean, but are now cosmopolitan.
        They prefer warm and dry environments and have a wide host range, including onion, garlic, leek,
        cucumber, cabbage, bedding plants, potato, melon, tomato, sugar beet, and weedy grasses. T. tabaci
        primarily feeds on conditions. It typically overwinters in small grains, clover, and alfalfa.
        Virus transmission may differ based on thrips gender, virus isolate, and source plant of virus.
        The onion thrips (Thrips tabaci) and Western flower thrips (Frankliniella occidentalis) are the
        main thrips types attacking vegetables.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Thrips_IPM_Recomm">The most effective management strategies rely on exclusion of infected plants and vector thrips.\n
Blue or yellow sticky cards are attractive to thrips, and are useful for monitoring populations.\n
Removal of infected (or suspected plants is crucial, as is control of weeds that may harbor the virus or thrips.\n
Reflective mulches have been demonstrated to reduce spread of TSWV in some systems (they are thought to cause confusion in thrips).\n
Contact insecticides are often not effective against thrips due to oviposition in tissue, the presence of adults inside tight buds and migration from surrounding plants.\n
Systemic insecticides often do not kill thrips fast enough to slow epidemics.\n
Many thrips biotypes exist with resistance to one or more insecticides, rotation of chemicals is vital to management.\n
Please consult your local supplier.\n</string>

    <!-- Tomato leaf miner-->
    <string name="Tomato_leaf_miner_Title">Tomato Leaf Miner</string>
    <string name="Tomato_leaf_miner">Tomato leaf miner, Tuta absluta is a micro lepidopteron moth with a
        high reproductive potential. There are about 10 – 12 generations per year. The total life cycle
        is completed within 30 – 35 days. Adults are nocturnal, hide between leaves at daytime, and are 5 – 7 mm
        long with a wingspan of 8 – 10 mm. Eggs are small cylindrical creamy white to yellow 0.35 mm long.
        The larva is cream in color with a characteristic dark head, the most important identifying
        characteristics are the filiform antennae (bead like antennae), silverfish to grey scales and
        characteristic black spot in the anterior wing. The larvae are becoming greenish to light pink in
        second to fourth instars. The larval period is the most damaging period which is completed within 12 – 15 days.
        \nTuta absluta is a devastating pest of tomato. It originated from South America. Recently tuta absoluta is
        considered to be a serious threat to tomato production. Each female can lay 250 – 300 eggs in her life time.
        This pest is crossing borders and devastating tomato production in both protected areas and open fields.
        The infestation of tuta absoluta was also reported on potato, aubergine and common beans.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_leaf_miner_IPM_Recomm">Tuta absoluta is a very challenging pest to control.\n
Effectiveness of chemical control is limited due to the insect’s nature as well as to its rapid capability to develop insecticide resistant strains.\n
The use of biological remedies is still largely underdeveloped and not ready to combat this pest effectively and in a cost effective way.\n
Sex pheromone traps are used as an early detection tool. Mass trapping and lure and kill application of pheromone has been found to be effective to control tuta abloluta.\n
Various active substance can be applied in combination with bio=rational control tactics.\n
Please consult your local supplier.\n</string>

    <!-- Cutworm -->
    <string name="Tomato_Cutworm_Title">Cutworm</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Cutworm">Cutworm, Peridroma saucia, the pearly underwing or variegated cutworm,
        is a species of moth of the family Noctuidae. Fat, basically gray, brown, or black caterpillar
        that is 40 to 50 mm long when full grown. It has 3 pairs of legs near the head and 5 pairs of
        fleshy prologs. Cutworms are active at night, young caterpillars climb on leaves, and the older
        caterpillar severs seedling stems near the ground. Cutworms hide during the day in soil burrows
        at the bases of plants.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Cutworm_IPM_Recomm">Destroy plat residues by tilling before plantation, especially when tomatoes follow a good host crop for cutworms (e.g. alfalfa or beans and cover crops that include legumes).\n
Manage weeds surrounding the field before planting.\n
Kill and till under or remove weeds, as cutworms will shelter in living and dead weeds.\n
If pupae are overwintering, only getting rid of host plants may not prevent damage.\n
During the season monitor the ground to detect damage.\n</string>

    <!-- Spider mites -->
    <string name="Tomato_Spider_Mites_Title">Spider Mites</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Spider_Mites">Spider mites are members of the Acari family Tetranychidae, which
        includes about 1,200 species. They generally live on the undersides of leaves of plants, where
        they may spin protective silk webs, and they can cause damage by puncturing the plant cells to
        feed. Plants take on a bronzed appearance. Upon closer inspection, stippling can be seen on
        individual leaves. Affected leaves eventually die and turn brown. \nWhile spider mites are generally
        present low at their initial population leaves are low. However, because mites have relatively short
        life cycles (under ideal conditions, a generation can be completed in a week time) and because hot dry
        weather conditions favor developmental rates, their populations rapidly escalate. \nAlthough small in size,
        the cumulative effect of many mites results in the rapid deterioration of tomato plants. In fact,
        by the time damage becomes apparent, many generations of mites have already occurred, and present
        population consists of all life stages. \nSpider mites tend to congregate on lower leaf surfaces,
        usually beginning on bottom leaves and working their way upper leaves. Spider mites damage plants
        by inserting their stylet mouthparts into individual plant cells and withdrawing cellular liquids and
        contents. Removal of chlorophyll results in the aforementioned stippling. The coalescence of dead cells
        results in the bronzed/brown appearance of leaves/plants.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Spider_Mites_IPM_Recomm">The key to mite control is through spray coverage and timely follow-up treatments.\n\n
Through spray coverage
Especially important when using oils and soaps because these two materials require direct contact with the active mite stages.\n
Once dried, oils and soaps offer no residual control.\n
Thorough spray coverage is critical when attempting to control mites. Factors complicating thorough coverage include; mites favouring undersides of leaves; mites concentrated on lower leaves, many of which lie on the ground; dense foliage; and a webbing (produced by mites) which shields mites from miticide treatments.\n
Timely follow-up treatments are required because initial spray treatments have little effect against mite eggs.\n
And once 6-legged larvae emerge from eggs, they proceed with unimpeded development. Thus the necessity of the second spray treatment application 2 to 3 days after the initial treatment.\n
All eggs will have hatched and no mites will have attained adult status to deposit additional eggs to begin the mite population buildup anew. As with the first spray treatment, thorough coverage must be attained with the follow-up treatment.\n
Once mite populations have been eliminated, plants will produce new foliage, and regain a healthy form.\n
</string>

    <!-- Bollworm -->
    <string name="Tomato_Bollworm_Title">Bollworm</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bollworm">African bollworm is a species of moth in the Lepidoptera order of
        the family Noctuidae. It is a major pest in cotton and one of the most polyphagous and cosmopolitan
        pest species. African bollworm caterpillar is initially pale green, sometimes with black dots,
        and a pattern of thin dark lines running along the body, the lines being darker around the second
        and third segments. The severity of the damage varies between crops, regions and locations, and between
        seasons. Caterpillars of the African bollworm feed on leaves, buds, growing points, flowers and fruit.
        Leaf damage reduces leaf area, which can slow plant growth. Feeding on flowers and fruit causes the main
        damage. Flower feeding can prevent fruit formation. Caterpillars usually bore clean, circular holes through
        fruits/pods. Excrements (faeces / waste) of the feeding caterpillars are placed away from damaged plant
        parts. The holes serve as entry points for secondary infection by diseases causing fruit decay. One
        caterpillar can damage several fruits/pods. Once they burrow into the fruits/pods they are difficult
        to reach and to control with insecticides.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bollworm_IPM_Recomm">Adequate identification/monitoring of different life stages and damage symptoms\n
Monitoring (field inspection, use of pheromone traps, etc), use a trap crop (e.g. African marigold) planted every 8 rows\n
Remove and destroy infected fruit and infested plants after harvest (burn or make compost)\n
Plough soil after harvesting to expose pupae to sunlight and natural enemies.\n
Allow natural enemies to flourish and Conserve natural enemies (Trichogramma pertiosum or T. achaeae, Macrolophus pygmaeus)\n</string>


    <!-- Disease-->

    <!-- Bacterial speck-->
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Speck_Title">Bacterial Speck</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Speck">Bacterial speck is caused by rod-shaped, bacterium Pseudomonas
        syringae pv. Tomato. Bacterial speck does not affect solanaceous crops but may survive on non – host
        plants. Tiny (0.15 cm) diameter dark spots appear on leaves, surrounded by yellow halos. However,
        as with bacterial spot and bacterial canker, the fruit symptoms are most characteristic. The numerous
        specks that develop on young green fruit are slightly raised 0.08 to 0.15 cm in diameter, and have
        well – defined margins. The specks are considerably smaller than the spots caused by bacterial spot,
        do not penetrate the fruit deeply, and can be scraped off with a fingernail. Although bacterial speck
        seldom reduces yields greatly, it can harm fruit quality. Cool wet conditions favor Infection.
        Epidemics often follow rainstorms that cause abrasion of leaves and splash soil onto the foliage. P. syringe pv.
        Tomato overwinters in seed, in plant debris in soil, and on many other plants.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Speck_IPM_Recomm">A combination of cultural practices is often needed to control bacterial speck and many other diseases.\n
Plant disease free transplants far enough apart so that the plants will not be crowded after they are fully grown, in order to help the foliage dry rapidly by good ventilation.\n
Water at the base of the plants, and in the morning rather than the evening, to minimize the amount of time that the leaves are wet.\n
Remove as much plant debris as possible in the fall and promptly plow under or bury the reaming residue.\n
Rotate crops so that tomatoes are grown in the same ground only three or four years.\n
Avoid working with plants when foliage is wet to avoid spreading disease – causing micro- organisms.\n
When the disease appears, change from overhead sprinkler to furrow irrigation\n
Destroying weeds around a tomato field or garden will help to reduce survival of the causal bacterium.\n
Fungicides also can help to control this disease.\n
A fixed copper product can help control spread of bacterial speck if applications begin when the first symptoms appear.\n
</string>

    <!-- Bacteria spot-->
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Spot_Title">Bacterial Spot</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Spot">Bacterial spot is caused by the Bacterium xanthomonas campestris pv. Vesicatoria.
        Bacterial spot is one of the most dangerous tomato diseases in existence, since it spreads rapidly
        and is very difficult to control. It infects both tomato and pepper. Spots that appear on leaves
        and stems are small (0.30 cm across), circular to irregular in shape, and have a slightly greasy feel.
        Unlike similar sized spots caused by the fungus septoria lycopersici, those caused by the bacterial
        spot pathogen do not develop grayish brown centers. As lesions enlarge, they often become surrounded by a
        yellow halo. If spots are numerous, they begin to grow together, and leaves wither and turn brown.
        \nFruit symptoms are more distinctive than leaf or stem symptoms. Spots on green fruit first appear
        as black, raised, pimple – like dots surrounded by water soaked areas. As the spots enlarge to 0.6 to 1.3 cm,
        they become gray – brown and scabby with sunken pitted centers. The bacterium overwinters on the surface of
        seeds, in infected debris, and in soil. It is commonly brought into fields on infected transplants.
        Warm rainy weather favors rapid spread of bacterial spot.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Spot_IPM_Recomm">To control bacterial spot, a combination of cultural
        practices is often needed. These practices, which also will help to reduce the risk of many other diseases, include the following:
A combination of cultural practices is often needed to control bacterial spot and many other diseases.\n
Plant disease free transplants far enough apart so that the plants will not be crowded after they are fully grown, in order to help the foliage dry rapidly by good ventilation.\n
Water at the base of the plants, and in the morning rather than the evening, to minimize the amount of time that the leaves are wet.\n
Remove as much plant debris as possible in the fall and promptly plow under or bury the reaming residue.\n
Rotate crops so that tomatoes are grown in the same ground only three or four years.\n
Avoid working with plants when foliage is wet to avoid spreading disease – causing micro- organisms.\n
When the disease appears, change from overhead sprinkler to furrow irrigation\n
Destroying weeds around a tomato field or garden will help to reduce survival of the causal bacterium.\n
Fungicides also can help to control this disease.\n
A fixed copper product can help control spread of bacterial speck if applications begin when the first symptoms appear.\n
</string>

    <!--Bacterial wilt-->
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Wilt_Title">Bacterial Wilt</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Wilt">Bacterial Wilt is caused by the pathogen bacterium Ralstonia
        solanacearum and is quite common in the moist soils. This bacterium lives in the soil and will
        work its way quickly through the roots and up the stem of the plants. Mature, fruit-bearing
        plants are affected in mid-summer. The first symptom is wilting of a few leaves. This often
        goes unnoticed. Soon thereafter, the entire plant wilts suddenly and dies. Such dramatic symptoms
        occur when the weather is hot (30\u00B0-35\u00B0C), and soil moisture is plentiful. Under less conducive
        conditions, wilt and decline will be slower, and numerous adventitious roots often form on the lower
        stems. In both cases, a brownish discoloration is present, first in the vascular system, and in advanced
        cases, spreading into the pith and cortex. The roots will exhibit varying degrees of decay. \nPlant infection
        can also occur through stem injuries caused by cultural practices or insect damage. In some cases,
        plant-to-plant spread can occur when bacteria move from roots of infected plants to roots of nearby
        healthy plants, often via irrigation practices. Spread of bacteria by aerial means and subsequent
        plant contamination through foliage is not known to occur, thus making R. solanacearum a non-airborne
        pathogen. High temperatures (29-35°C) play a major role in pathogen growth and disease development.
        Several other factors that may affect pathogen survival in soil and water may also favours disease
        development, including soil type and structure, soil moisture content, organic matter in soil, water
        pH and salt content, and the presence of antagonist microorganisms. </string>
    <string name="Tomato_Bacterial_Wilt_IPM_Recomm">Before plantation:
Consider an effective weed control in and around tomato fields and aquatic weed control around irrigation ponds.\n
Apply 3-4 years rotation and cover crops for infested fields to reduce R. solanacearum, weeds and nematodes.\n
Do not irrigate rotation and cover crops with R. solanacearum contaminated pond or surface water, avoid infestation.\n
Use well drained and levelled fields and do not use low-lying areas of the field.\n
Raise soil pH to 7.5-7.6 and increase available calcium (liming).\n
Consider using infested fields (after 3-4 years rotation) during cooler months for tomato production.\n\n

During production:\n\n

Exclude the pathogen by applying strict sanitation practices (pathogen free irrigation water, transplants, stakes, machinery, etc.).\n
Chlorinate your irrigation water continuously if you are using surface water or R. solanacearum infested pond water.\n
Continue an effective weed control in and around tomato fields and irrigation ponds.\n
Irrigate based on water need, avoid over irrigation.\n
Apply plant resistance inducer, such as Actigard (Syngenta) if you are using moderately resistant cultivars.\n
Actigard enhances resistance against this disease if it is used in combination with moderately resistant cultivars.\n</string>

    <!--Black root rot-->
    <string name="Tomato_Black_Root_Rot_Title">Black Root Rot</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Black_Root_Rot">Black root rot is caused by plant-pathogenic fungus Thielaviopsis basicola.
        It is a soil-borne fungus that causes black root rot. It has a wide host range. Symptoms of black root rot
        are typical of many other root rots or root problems. Some of these symptoms may include yellowing of the
        plant, defoliation, stunting or wilting, as well as red brown lenticels and swelling of the crown.
        The fungus produces black spores in roots that when abundant cause the black lesions that are typical
        of black root rot. Thielaviopsis basicola can also attack seedlings, and the hypocotyl below the soil
        may become infected along with the roots. Infected tissue is first seen as elongated red lesions, which
        eventually turn black. In severe cases the entire root may appear black. Stunting of tap-root growth also
        occurs. Plants may develop new roots following infection, but they can only support the plant when sufficient
        moisture is available. If unchecked, root rot can lead to collar rot, causing wilting of leaves and tender stems.
        The Thielaviopsis state produces dark Chlamydospores are a type of resting spore and may survive in soil for many years.
        These spores are stimulated to germinate by compounds produced by the roots. Favourable conditions include a soil pH
        between 5 and 8.5 with a soil temperature between 12 and 21°C. Saturated soil can also increase disease, as well as
        increase the overall stress on the plant. The fungus can spread from infected roots to healthy roots if they come
        into contact. Spores can also be splashed from pot to pot when watering.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Black_Root_Rot_IPM_Recomm">Stress or adverse growing conditions can also increase the likelihood of disease development, and include factors such as saturated soils, salt build up, and adverse temperatures.\n
Another environmental factor is soil pH. Maintaining a soil pH below 5.6 has been shown to decrease severity of symptoms.\n
Several fungicides have proven effective, but may be most effective when used preventatively or at first sign of disease.\n
Fungicides cannot compensate for poor sanitation or environmental controls.\n</string>

    <!--Early blight (Alternaria leaf spot)-->
    <string name="Tomato_Early_Blight_Title">Early Blight (Alternaria leaf spot)</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Early_Blight">Early blight is a fungal disease, caused by the Alternaria sp. Alternaria
        solani. Like septoria leaf spot, early blight is common in open field and the two diseases may attack
        the same plants. Premature loss of lower leaves is the most obvious symptom of the disease. Brown to
        black spots, 0.6 to 1.3 cm in diameter with dark edges, appear on lower leaves. Spots frequently merge,
        forming irregular blotches. Dark, concentric rings often appear in leaf spots, resulting in the “target”
        appearance suggested by the common name. Leaves turn yellow and dry up when only a few spots are present.
        The fungus occasionally attacks fruit at the stem end, causing large, sunken areas with concentric rings
        and a black, velvety appearance. Warm, wet weather favors rapid spread of early blight. A. solani also can
        infect potato. Early blight can infect plants at any stage during the growing season but usually progresses
        most rapidly after plants have set fruit.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Early_Blight_IPM_Recomm">To control early blight, a combination of cultural practices is often needed. These practices, which also will help to reduce the risk of many other diseases, include the following:\n
Plant disease – free transplants far enough apart so that the plants will not be crowded after they are fully grown, in order to help the foliage dry rapidly.\n
Water at the base of the plants, and in the morning rather than the evening, to minimize the amount of time that the leaves are wet.\n
Remove as much plant debris as possible in the fall and promptly plow under or bury the reaming residue.\n
Rotate cereal and legume crops so that tomatoes are grown in the same ground only three or four years. In addition, avoid potato in rotations.\n
Harvest all ripe fruit at every picking to avoid infecting other fruit.\n
Resistant varieties of tomatoes provide partial resistance to early blight.\n
Avoid working with plants when foliage is wet to avoid spreading disease  causing micro organisms\n
Remove weeds and alternative hosts around a tomato field\n
Fungicides also can help to control early blight please consult your supplier\n</string>

    <!--Fusarium crown and root rot-->
    <string name="Tomato_Fusarium_Crown_Title">Fusarium Crown and Root Rot</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fusarium_Crown">Fusarium crown and root rot, caused by the fungus Fusarium oxysporum f. sp.
        radicis-lycopersici. Plants infected with crown rot are stunted and yellow. Symptoms begin on older leaves
        and progress to entire plant. The entire plat eventually turns brown and dies. The roots are brown and
        may rot away due to secondary pathogens. The stems often have brown to secondary pathogens.
        Reddish to brown discoloration of the stem cortex when sliced lengthwise. The stems often have
        brown vascular streaks and dark brown lesions often occur on the stem near the soil line.
        Disease development is faster in cool wet soils, and the problem is often severe in greenhouse crops.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fusarium_Crown_IPM_Recomm">To minimize losses from fusarium crown rot, it is advisable to plant resistant varieties, and many resistant varieties are available.\n
Infection enters the plant through wounds, but it may also be seed born.\n
Fungicide drenches is effective to control the disease please consult your supplier\n</string>

    <!--Fusarium wilt-->
    <string name="Tomato_Fusarium_Wilt_Title">Fusarium Wilt</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fusarium_Wilt">Fusarium wilt is caused by the fungus Fusarium oxyspourm f. sp.
        Lycopersici. It attacks only certain tomato cultivars. Plants infected by this soil-dwelling
        fungus show leaf yellowing and wilting that progress upward from the base of the stem, initially,
        only one side of a leaf midrib, one branch, or one side of a plant will be affected, the symptoms
        soon spread to the remainder of the plant wilted leaves usually drop prematurely. Affected plants
        die early and produce few, if any fruit. \nSplitting open an infected stem reveals brownish streaks
        extending up and down the stem. These discolored streaks are the water-conducting tissue, which
        becomes plugged during attack by the fungus, leading to wilting of the leaves. Plants are susceptible
        at all stages of development, but symptoms are most obvious at or soon after flowering. This disease
        severely attack potato, eggplant and pepper. High rainfall, over irrigation and poor drainage will
        create conducive environment for the disease.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fusarium_Wilt_IPM_Recomm">To minimize losses form fusarium wilt, it is advisable to plant resistant varieties, and many resistant varieties are available\n
Resistant varieties may become infected, but disease will not be as severe as with susceptible varieties and a reasonable yield should still be obtained.\n
In addition, plant on disease free seed or transplants in well drained, disease free soil\n
Rotate at least four years away from tomatoes to reduce populations of the fungus in soil, and remove and destroy infected plant residue.\n
In greenhouse or seedbeds, disinfest soil by treating with steam. Please consult your supplier.\n</string>


    <!-- Gray leaf spot-->
    <string name="Tomato_Gray_Leaf_Spot_Title">Gray Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Gray_Leaf_Spot">Gray leaf spot is a common disease of tomato and pepper in warm,
        humid production areas. The disease can be caused by two different fungi of the genus Stemphylium,
        namely Fungus Stemphylium floridanum and Stemphylium botryosum. Small brownish black specks first
        appear on the undersides of the leaves. These later develop into larger necrotic areas, and the
        tissue often falls out, leaving a shot hole type appearance, spots may be surrounded by a yellow
        halo. Yellowing, leaf drop, and defoliation may occur in severe cases.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Gray_Leaf_Spot_IPM_Recomm">The fungus can survive from year to year on solanaceous weeds, so weed control is important.\n
Many commercial varieties are resistant.\n
Leaf moisture from rains or dew increases disease severity.\n
Fungicides may be used as recommended. Please consult your supplier.\n</string>

    <!--Gray mold ( Botrytis cinerea)-->
    <string name="Tomato_Gray_Mold_Title">Gray Mold ( Botrytis cinerea)</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Gray_Mold">Gray mold, caused by the fungus botrytis cinerea, is a common disease
        of greenhouse grown tomatoes. This disease is characterized by a light gray fuzzy growth that
        appears on stems and leaves. Soft of the stem end of the fruit can also occur. Botrytis infections
        are most severe in greenhouses with moderate temperatures, high humidity, and stagnant air.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Gray_Mold_IPM_Recomm">Increasing ventilation and air circulation to reduce humidity levels can be helpful\n
Timely fungicide applications. Please consult your supplier.\n</string>

    <!--Late blight-->
    <string name="Tomato_Late_Blight_Title">Late Blight</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Late_Blight">Late blight disease is caused by an oomycete or water mold, microorganism
        Phytophthora infestans. It is serious potato and tomato disease. Late blight can devastate tomato
        plantings during periods of cool rainy weather. Late blight may infect either young (upper) or old (lower)
        leaves. It first appears as water – soaked areas that enlarge rapidly. Forming irregular, greenish black
        blotches, giving the plant a frost – damaged appearance. The undersides of the leaves often show a downy
        white growth in moist weather. Infection of green or ripe fruit produces large, irregularly shaped brown
        blotches. Infected fruits rapidly deteriorate into foul – smelling masses. Stems and branches are also
        infected; the typical symptoms are brown – black spots on stems and branches. Late blight usually appears
        during persistent cool wet weather, or when cool night temperatures cause frequent heavy dews. P.
        infestans causes similar symptoms on potatoes and can spread from potatoes to tomatoes.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Late_Blight_IPM_Recomm">To control late blight, a combination of cultural practices is often needed. These practices, which also will help to reduce the risk of many other diseases, include the following:\n
Plant disease – free transplants far enough apart so that the plants will not be crowded after they are fully grown, in order to help the foliage dry rapidly.\n
Water at the base of the plants, and in the morning rather than the evening, to minimize the amount of time that the leaves are wet.\n
Remove as much plant debris as possible in the fall and promptly plow under or bury the reaming residue.\n
Rotate crops so that tomatoes are grown in the same ground only three or four years. In addition, avoid rotating with potato.\n
Avoid working with plants when foliage is wet to avoid spreading disease – causing micro- organisms\n
Fungicides also can help to control Late blight. Please consult your supplier.\n
</string>


    <!-- Powdery mildew-->
    <string name="Tomato_Powdery_Mildew_Title">Powdery Mildew</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Powdery_Mildew">Powdery mildew is caused by funguses Oidium neolycopersici
        or Leveillula taurica. It causes severe white powder on all aerial parts of tomato, excluding the fruit.
        Leaf symptoms of Oidiopsis taurica consist of yellow blotches or spots on the upper leaf surface.
        A white powdery growth occurs on the underside of the leaves. This fungus penetrates within the leaf
        tissue. For Oidium neolycopersici, symptoms first appear as small, powdery white colonies on the upper
        surface of the leaves. The fungal growth does not penetrate deeply into the leaf. The lower surface of
        the foliage may also be affected during later stages when the disease is severe .With both pathogens,
        the older colonies of the fungus may turn a dirty white colour with age. The severely affected leaves
        turn yellow, then brown, and later become shriveled. Generally, the lower leaves are affected first
        and the disease gradually moves up the plant. \nBoth fungi are prolific producers of spores that
        are readily dispersed by wind and rain. Many cycles of disease development occur during the plant’s
        growing period. The fungus spore is also spread by insect pests (thrips, aphids and whiteflies) and
        field workers, but to a lesser extent. The fungus is not seed borne. Spore germination and infection
        are favored by wide fluctuations of temperature and humidity during the day and night, which create
        periods of leaf wetness. O. taurica is favored by high relative humidity (greater than 85%) at night
        followed by warm (25° C), less humid conditions during the day. For O. neolycopersici, optimum disease
        development occurs at 22 °C particularly after 16 or 24 hours of leaf wetness; symptoms can appear
        within 7 days from the time that the spore lands on the leaf surface.
</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Powdery_Mildew_IPM_Recomm">Avoid high rates of nitrogen, which make plants more susceptible to infection.\n
Avoid crowding and shading, which lead to the development of leaf wetness and conditions that promote infection.\n
Avoid overhead irrigation for the same reason.\n
Avoid planting young tomato plants while diseased plants remain nearby.\n
Control weeds around the planting site since both fungi have a wide host range and could persist on these plants during the growing season or during the off-season.\n
</string>


    <!-- Root knot nematodes-->
    <string name="Tomato_Root_Knot_Nematods_Title">Root Knot Nematodes</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Root_Knot_Nematods">The root-knot nematode (Meloidogyne spp.) is a major plant pathogen,
        affecting several solanaceous crops worldwide. Nematode infestations damage the plant roots, and therefore
        symptoms reflect poorly functioning root systems. Above ground symptoms of severe root knot and stubby
        root nematode infestations include patches of chlorotic, stunted, necrotic, or wilted plants. Plants
        appear sluggish and appear off color even though adequate nutrition is provided. When infected plants
        are pulled up, roots are “knotted” and swollen with growths which may resulting a matted root system in severe cases.
        \nNematode-infested plants are more susceptible to moisture or temperature stress and exhibit stress symptoms earlier
        than other plants. Furthermore, root systems that have been damaged by nematodes are often more susceptible to
        infection by soil-inhabiting fungi such as Fusarium and Verticillium species. \nFeeding by root knot nematodes
        results in characteristic galls on roots. Severely galled roots may appear malformed and the root system
        shortened and thickened. In general, lighter, sandy soils favor nematode infection and result in more severe damage to roots.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Root_Knot_Nematods_IPM_Recomm">In fields infested with root knot nematodes, crop rotation may not be feasible because of their extensive host range;\n
Care is needed in the selection of rotation crops because some may be good alternate hosts.\n
Alternation with a ”trap crop” such as Elbon cereal rye which limits nematode reproduction may be effective.\n
It is advisable to plant resistant varieties, and many resistant varieties are available.\n
Soil solarization may help to lower the nematodes in the top layers of the soil and avoid an early infestation of the plants.\n
Roots are likely to become infested as the season progresses by nematodes that survived in the deeper soil layers.\n</string>

    <!-- Damping off-->
    <string name="Tomato_Damping_Off_Title">Damping Off</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Damping_Off">Damping off is caused by fungus or fungus-like microorganisms, Pythium spp.,
        Phytophthora spp., Fusarium spp., Rhizoctonia solani, and other fungi. Affected plants usually occur in
        patches in nursery beds or in low parts of sloped fields. In level fields, affected plants are generally
        found in scattered areas. \nDamping off may occur before and/or after emergence. In pre-emergence damping
        off, the seeds fail to emerge after sowing. They become soft, mushy, turn brown, and decompose as a
        consequence of seed infection. In post-emergence damping-off, the seedling emerges from the soil but dies
        shortly afterwards. The affected portions (roots, hypocotyls and perhaps the crown of the plant) are pale
        brown, soft, water soaked, and thinner than non-affected tissue. Infected stems collapse. Stunting of plants
        due to root rot or collar rot may also occur.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Damping_Off_IPM_Recomm">use plug transplants and a soilless pathogen-free growth medium\n
Water seedlings only when the soil or growth medium is dry, preferably in the morning to allow drying to occur by the late afternoon.\n
Avoid contact with ground soil or other sources of contamination.\n
Choose well-drained locations and Keep the seedbed well ventilated and Sow on raised beds.\n
Avoid overcrowding of plants and the movement of infested soil or contaminated plant material into the nursery bed.\n
Workers should clean their hands and tools before handling healthy plants.\n
Surface irrigation ponds may be a source of fungal contamination.\n
Pots or transplant containers should be new or treated recently with a disinfectant (10% household bleach) or\n
</string>

    <!--Septoria leaf spot-->
    <string name="Tomato_Septoria_Leaf_Spot_Title">Septoria Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Septoria_Leaf_Spot">Septoria leaf spot is caused by a fungus, Septoria lycopersici.
        It is one of the most destructive diseases of tomato foliage and is particularly severe in areas where
        wet, humid weather persists for extended periods. This disease first appears as small, water-soaked
        spots that soon become circular spots about 0.3 cm in diameter. The lesions gradually develop grayish
        white centers with dark edges. The light colored centers of these spots are the most distinctive
        symptom of septoria leaf spot. When conditions are favorable, fungal fruiting bodies appear as
        tiny black specks in the centers of the spots. Spores are spread to new leaves by splashing rain.
        Heavily infected leaves turn yellow wither, and eventually fall off. Lower leaves are infected first.
        And the disease progresses upward if rainy weather persists. Defoliation can be sever after periods
        of prolonged warm, wet weather. Infection can occur at any stage of plant development but appears most
        frequently after plants have begun to set fruit. The fungus survives the winter in tomato debris. </string>
    <string name="Tomato_Septoria_Leaf_Spot_IPM_Recomm">To control septoria leaf spot a combination of cultural practices is often needed.\n
This practices is often needed. These practices, which also will help to reduce the risk of many other diseases, include the following:\n
Plant disease – free transplants far enough apart so that the plants will not be crowded after they are fully grown, in order to help the foliage dry rapidly.\n
Water at the base of the plants, and in the morning rather than the evening, to minimize the amount of time that the leaves are wet.\n
Remove as much plant debris as possible in the fall and promptly plow under or bury the reaming residue.\n
Rotate crops so that tomatoes are grown in the same ground only three or four years.\n
Avoid working with plants when foliage is wet to avoid spreading disease causing micro- organisms\n
Fungicides also can help to control septoria leaf spot\n</string>

    <!-- Tomato spotted wilt virus (TSWV)-->
    <string name="Tomato_Spotted_Wilt_Virus_Title">Tomato Spotted Wilt Virus (TSWV)</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Spotted_Wilt_Virus">One of the most common virus disease is Tomato Spotted Wilt Virus (TSWV).
        TSWV causes distinctive yellow ring spots on mature fruit. Foliage also can be affected; plants
        are usually stunted and tip leaves show a purplish discoloration. Sometimes, it may lead to
        confusion with water deficiency. Thrips, which are small (2mm long) brownish yellow insects
        spread the virus. Plants can be affected as transplants while growing in a greenhouse; after
        transplanting, stunting and failure to set fruit may be the most noticeable symptoms.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Spotted_Wilt_Virus_IPM_Recomm">To minimize losses from TSWV, It is advisable to plant resistant varieties, and many resistant varieties are available.\n
Planting only certified virus free transplants. It is the best technique for managing viruses.\n
It is helpful to verify that greenhouse used to produce transplants conducts a vigorous program to control aphids and thrips.\n
There is now way to “cure” a virus infected plant. However, removing the infected plant as soon as symptoms are found can help prevent spread by insects to healthy plants.\n
Many viruses that infect tomato also infect peppers and potatoes; so avoid planting these crops next to each other.\n
Thrips control may also be beneficial in the transplant and early season phases.\n</string>

    <!-- Tomato mosaic virus (ToMV) -->
    <string name="Tomato_Mosaic_Virus_Title">Tomato mosaic virus (ToMV)</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Mosaic_Virus">Symptoms can be found during any growth stage and all plant parts are affected.
        Generally, infected plants have a light or dark green mottling or mosaic with distortion of younger leaves,
        and stunting to varying degrees. Severely affected leaves may have a “fernlike” appearance and may show raised
        dark green areas. Fruit set may be severely reduced in affected plants. There may be internal browning of the
        fruit wall, yellow blotches and necrotic spots may occur on green or ripe fruit. Some strains can cause yellow
        mottling of leaves, others cause dark necrotic streaks in stems, petioles, leaves or fruit, or other symptoms
        to occur. Symptoms are influenced by environmental conditions such as day length, temperature, and light intensity
        as well as by variety, plant age at infection, and virulence of tomato mosaic virus (ToMV) strain. On susceptible
        cultivars, symptoms may range from severe to none. Occasionally, dual infection with potato virus X in tomato
        causes severe symptom development known as “double streak”. Some symptoms caused by ToMV resemble symptoms induced
        by hormones such as 2, 4-D. \n\nThe virus is seed-borne. Infested tomato seeds can be the source of infection
        and the means by which the virus can be disseminated over large distances. The virus can be spread by horticultural
        workers on contaminated hands, clothing, and tools during routine horticultural operations such as transplanting,
        tying, pruning, grafting, pollinating, cultivating, spraying, watering, and picking. ToMV is a closely related
        strain of tobacco mosaic virus (TMV). The virus is quite stable under adverse environmental conditions and can
        persist in plant debris in dry soil for 2 years or in moist soil for 1 month or in root debris in fallow soil
        for 22 months. It can also persist in greenhouse structures for long periods of time. Healthy seedlings planted
        into contaminated soil can be infected through minor wounds caused by damage to roots. The virus may also be
        present in water used for irrigation. Dissemination of tiny particles of contaminated soil by wind is also possible.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Mosaic_Virus_IPM_Recomm">Use seed from healthy plants only.\n
Dry heating seed at 70°C for 4 days or at 82-85°C for 24hr will help to eliminate surface-borne virus.\n
ToMV on the seed coat can be eliminated by soaking seed for 15 min in 100 g/l of tri-sodium phosphate solution (TSP), rinsing thoroughly, and spreading seeds out to dry.\n
Use a minimum 2-year rotation.\n
Avoid following tomato crops with susceptible crops such as tobacco, pepper, eggplant, or cucurbits.\n
Dip hands in milk while handling plants every 5 minutes (more often if different lots of plants are handled).\n
Rubber gloves will protect hands.\n
Remove diseased plants from the field as soon as virus symptoms are noticed.\n
This will reduce the spread of the virus by direct contact between plants.\n
Disinfect tools, stakes, and equipment before moving from diseased areas to healthy areas.\n
This can be done by:\n
(1) Heating or steaming at 150°C for 30 minutes;\n
(2) Soaking 10 minutes in 1% formaldehyde or a 1:10 dilution of a 5.25% sodium hypochlorite,\n
Work in diseased areas last after working in unaffected parts of a field.\n
Wash clothing that comes into contact with ToMV-infected plants with hot water and a detergent.\n</string>

    <!--Tomato yellow leaf curl virus (TYLCV)-->
    <string name="Tomato_Yellow_Leaf_Virus_Title">Tomato Yellow Leaf Curl Virus (TYLCV)</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Yellow_Leaf_Virus">Tomato yellow leaf curl virus can infect a relatively wide
        range of plant species tomato is the host to which the virus is best adapted and that facilitates
        the buildup of the virus to high incidences in the field. Other hosts include solanaceous crops,
        which may develop symptomless infections, and weeds. Tomato yellow leaf curl virus (TYLCV), a
        disease that threatens both commercial and home tomato production fields. It is a DNA virus from
        the genus Begomovirus and the family Geminiviridae. TYLCV causes the most destructive disease of
        tomato, and it can be found in tropical and subtropical regions causing severe economic losses.
        This virus is transmitted by an insect vector the whitefly Bemisia tabaci. \nThe primary host for
        TYLCV is the tomato plant, and other host Solanaceae plants.  Infected tomato plants initially
        show stunted and erect or upright plant growth; plants infected at an early stage of growth will
        show severe stunting. However, the most diagnostic symptoms are those in leaves. Leaves of infected
        plants are small and curl upward, show strong crumpling and inter – veinal and marginal yellowing.
        The internodes of infected plants become shortened and, together with the stunted growth, plants
        often take on a bushy appearance like growth. Flowers formed on infected plants commonly do not
        develop and fall off (abscise). Fruit production is dramatically reduced, particularly when plants
        are infected at an early age, and it is not uncommon for losses of 100% to be experienced in fields
        with heavily infected plants. \nTomato yellow leaf curl virus is undoubtedly one on the most damaging
        diseases of tomato, and it limits production of tomato in many tropical and subtropical areas of the world.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Yellow_Leaf_Virus_IPM_Recomm">The primary way the virus is spread over short distances is by the bemisia whitefly species.\n
Over long distance, the virus is primarily spread through the movement of infected plants; especially tomato disease symptoms to develop, infected symptomless plants could be unknowingly transported.\n
The virus also can be moved over long distance by virus- carrying whiteflies that are transported on tomatoes or other plants (e.g. ornamentals) or via high winds, hurricanes, or tropical storms. Strategies to effectively manage the disease include:\n\n
Before planting\n\n
Select TYLCV – resistant varieties\n
Use virus – and whitefly –free transplants.\n
Do not import tomato (or any potential whitefly host) transplants from areas known to have the virus.\n\n
During the growing season\n\n
Plant immediately after any tomato –free period\n
Avoid planting new fields near older fields (especially those with TYLCV- infected plants).\n
Manage whiteflies.\n
Cover plants with floating row covers of fine mesh to protect from whitefly infestations.\n
Rogue diseased plants when incidence of virus infection is low\n
Practice good weed management in and around fields to the extent feasible\n
After the growing season\n
Remove and destroy old crop residue and volunteers on a regional basis.\n</string>


    <!-- Disorder-->

    <!-- Blossom End Rot-->
    <string name="Tomato_Blossom_End_Rot_Title">Blossom End Rot</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Blossom_End_Rot">Blossom End Rot (BER) is a very common problem on green and
        ripe tomatoes. It is a deficiency of Calcium and is related to wide fluctuations in available
        moisture and Irrigation. The diagnostic symptom is a light tan lesion turning to a dark brown
        sunken area at the blossom end of the fruit. The lesion typically enlarges and becomes more sunken
        and leathery.  Although Blossom End Rot itself causes only local injury, secondary organisms
        frequently invade the lesion and cause complete rotting of the fruit. It often occurs in rapidly
        developing fruit during periods of hot, dry weather and tends to have the greatest impact on the
        earliest maturing fruit. Normally, fruit that are about half developed are the first to show symptoms.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Blossom_End_Rot_IPM_Recomm">To prevent Blossom End Rot, maintain a steady rate of plant growth without stress.\n
A consistent and ample supply of moisture can reduce the problem by helping to maintain a steady flow of calcium from the soil to the fruit.\n
Mulching also will help by conserving soil moisture.\n
Blossom End Rot is more serious when an excess of nitrogen fertilizer has been applied as it promotes excessive vegetative growth, which in turns increases transpiration surface area and prevents calcium transport and accumulation on the fruit.\n
Staking and pruning tomato plants also may increase the incidence of Blossom End Rot.\n
If Blossom End Rot occurs, remove the affected fruit so that the later-maturing fruit will develop normally.\n
Use of less susceptible cultivars\n
Avoid excessively high concentrations of potassium and magnesium as this reduces uptake and availability of calcium.\n
Application of calcium fertilizers before planting are commonly used to reduce the incidence of blossom end rot.\n
Fields which are difficult to irrigate uniformly or those with high salinity should be avoided.\n
Root injury caused by mechanical damage or disease can exacerbate this condition and should be avoided.\n</string>

    <!-- Sunscald in tomato -->
    <string name="Tomato_Sunscald_In_Tomato_Title">Sunscald In Tomato</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Sunscald_In_Tomato">Sunscald first appears as light patches on green or ripening
        fruit. Most often, sunscald develops on the side of the fruit that faces the sun during hot weather.
        As the patches grow, they may blister and may become grayish-white Affected sunscald tomatoes can
        develop black mold. It is more apparent on plants that have sparse foliage or those that may have
        previously lost a good deal of leaves to a leaf-defoliating disease. Sunscald is especially prevalent
        on previously shaded plant parts that have been suddenly exposed to the sun. The damaged areas are
        vulnerable to attack by insects, fungi, and bacteria.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Sunscald_In_Tomato_IPM_Recomm">Don’t over-prune tomato plants, especially in hot climates. If you leave extra branches on plants, you’ll provide extra shade for fruit.\n
Practice controls for leaf diseases in order to prevent defoliation that leaves the fruits more vulnerable to sunscald.\n
These practices may include crop rotation, proper sanitation, and the use of fungicides.\n
Plant varieties that are tolerant to disease. Specially, select varieties that tolerate Septoria leaf spot and early blight, two of the most common defoliating diseases.\n
</string>

    <!-- Fruit Macro Cracking-->
    <string name="Tomato_Fruit_Macro_Cracking_Title">Fruit Macro Cracking</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fruit_Macro_Cracking">Two types of cracks may develop on tomato fruit. Radial
        growth cracks radiate from the stem, and concentric cracks encircle the fruit, usually on the
        shoulders. Similar to Blossom End Rot, cracking is associated with raping fruit development
        and wide fluctuation in water availability to the plant. Fruit that has reached the ripening
        stage during dry weather may show considerable cracking if the dry period is followed by heavy
        rains and high temperatures.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fruit_Macro_Cracking_IPM_Recomm">As with Blossom End Rot, mulching and avoiding heavy applications of nitrogen fertilizer should help reduce fruit cracking.\n
Tomato varieties differ considerably in the amount and severity of cracking under climatic conditions.\n
</string>

    <!--Fruit Micro Cracking / Russeting-->
    <string name="Tomato_Fruit_Micro_Cracking_Russeting_Title">Fruit Micro Cracking / Russeting</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fruit_Micro_Cracking_Russeting">Fruit Russeting is characterized by multiple micro
        cracks in the tomato skin, also called cuticle cracking. Russeting decreases shelf life and, with time,
        can evolve into dark shoulders due to water loss. This further reduces visual appearance and fruits
        cannot be sold. The sequence of high and low fruit expansion rates combined with low fruit skin
        elasticity is responsible for russeting.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Fruit_Micro_Cracking_Russeting_IPM_Recomm">A combination of crop management practices, greenhouse temperature management, and irrigation strategies should be used to reduce the occurrence of this disorder.\n
Crop management practices include maintain a low but constant fruit growth rate, reducing the leaf/fruit ratio, installing a shade screen to avoid excess fruit temperatures.\n
Whenever possible, harvesting before pink stage effectively helps reducing fruit cracking. Air temperature should increase gradually from night to daytime and the difference between day and night air temperatures should be minimized to reduce fruit maturation period.\n
The most important control is based on irrigation management.\n
The best irrigation schedule will be specific for each growing situation. However, in all cases, the goal is to avoid high root pressure late in the day and/or early morning.\n
Regarding nutrition, it is important to provide the plant with the abundant supply of Calcium to reinforce cell wall division and integrity.\n
Cracking is an inherited tendency and different cultivars have different susceptibility to fruit cracking.\n
</string>

    <!-- Failure to set fruit-->
    <string name="Tomato_Failure_To_Set_Fruit_Title">Failure To Set Fruit</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Failure_To_Set_Fruit">High dry season temperatures can reduce the number of
        tomato fruit harvested in several ways. High day and night temperatures will reduce flower production
        on tomato plants. If the night temperatures are above 21 degree Celsius, flower production and
        pollination are reduced. High temperatures for several consecutive days, coupled with drought
        conditions, will lead to poor pollination and cause flowers to drop from the plants. Hot drying
        wind may intensify the problem. Plants sometimes drop their flowers when night temperatures are
        lower than 13 degrees Celsius.</string>
    <string name="Tomato_Failure_To_Set_Fruit_IPM_Recomm">The most favorable night range for tomato fruit set is between 14 and 20 degrees Celsius.\n</string>

    <string name="note_Title">Before you apply the recommended pesticides, Note the following points!</string>
    <string name="note">Use recommended and registered chemicals\n\n
    To prevent resistance development, rotate chemical mode of action groups.\n\n
    Prevent resistance development by rotating chemical mode of action groups.\n\n
    About rate of application, follow the label instructions given by the manufacturing company and local suppliers.\n\n
    Consider the crop type, the growth stage and spraying time, apply sufficient volume of water to ensure thorough coverage.\n\n
    Give attention how to use the personal protection equipment, re-entry period, pre-harvest interval (PHI) and other pertinent instructions and warnings.\n\n
    For better result, please consult your local specialist.
</string>

    <string name="popup_btn_Okay">Okay!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_splash_screen">SplashScreenActivity</string>

    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <!--
<string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
<string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
<string name="next">Next</string>
<string name="previous">Previous</string>

<string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
<string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
!-->
</resources>



